{
    "trivia": {
        "Entertainment": [
									{"question": "In what year were the Oscars first presented?",  "ans" : "1929",  "opt1" : "1933",  "opt2" : "1945",  "opt3" : "1954"},
									{"question": "Directed by Christopher Nolan in 2010, what film questioned reality with multilevel dream states and starred Leonardo Dicaprio?",  "ans" : "Inception",  "opt1" : "Splice",  "opt2" : "Memento",  "opt3" : "Insomnia"},
									{"question": "This movie is about a poor girl, who is really kind to everyone. She has a wicked step-mother, and two step-sisters. She has a lot of animal friends and even a fairy god-mother! What movie is this?",  "ans" : "Cinderella",  "opt1" : "Snow White",  "opt2" : "Beauty and the Beast",  "opt3" : "Sleeping Beauty"},
									{"question": "Directed in 1975 by Steven Spielberg, what movie about a great white shark was considered the first-ever summer blockbuster?",  "ans" : "Jaws",  "opt1" : "Jaws of the Pacific",  "opt2" : "Great White Death",  "opt3" : "Sharkwater"},
									{"question": "Also the name of a city in Morocco, what 1942 film starred Humphrey Bogart and featured the line 'I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship'?",  "ans" : "Casablanca",  "opt1" : "Marrakesh",  "opt2" : "Cleopatra",  "opt3" : "Cairo"},
									{"question": "Released in 1998, which of these mathematical terms was also the debut film of Darren Aronofsky?",  "ans" : "Pi",  "opt1" : "Tangent",  "opt2" : "Ellipse",  "opt3" : "Radial"},
									{"question": "What 2002 M. Night Shyalaman film starred Mel Gibson and Joaquin Phoenix and involved aliens?",  "ans" : "Signs",  "opt1" : "Devil",  "opt2" : "Unbreakable",  "opt3" : "Solaris"},
									{"question": "In 1960, Alfred Hitchcock directed a movie starring Anthony Perkins which featured a famous shower scene and one of the most famous movie motels. What was the films name?",  "ans" : "Psycho",  "opt1" : "Vertigo",  "opt2" : "Identity",  "opt3" : "Rope"},
									{"question": "A pregnant teen played by Ellen Page was the focal point for which 2007 Oscar-nominated film about life, love, and orange Tic-Tacs?",  "ans" : "Juno",  "opt1" : "Grace",  "opt2" : "Inside",  "opt3" : "Super"},
									{"question": "Which 2009 James Cameron film lost the Best Picture Academy Award to 'The Hurt Locker', a movie directed by his ex-wife, Kathryn Bigelow?",  "ans" : "Avatar",  "opt1" : "Red",  "opt2" : "Titanic",  "opt3" : "Up"},
									{"question": "his movie is about a boy who never grows up, and he can fly! He has a fairy called Tinkerbell and an enemy called Captain Hook! What movie is this?",  "ans" : "Peter Pan",  "opt1" : "101 Dalmatians",  "opt2" : "Tinkerbell and the Lost Treasure",  "opt3" : "The Fox and the Hound"},
									{"question": "This movie is about an animal, called Simba. Simba is a small cub, with a brave nature. He turns out to be king of his home, the Pride Lands! What movie is this?",  "ans" : "The Lion King",  "opt1" : "The Aristocats",  "opt2" : "The Fox and the Hound",  "opt3" : "Bambi"},
									{"question": "This is the most famous Disney character. He has many movies and television series. This character has a dog called Pluto. Do you know Who this is?",  "ans" : "Mickey Mouse",  "opt1" : "Donald Duck",  "opt2" : "Goofy",  "opt3" : "Minnie Mouse"},
									{"question": "This is about a dog that is a star in Hollywood. He thinks that everything he does is real until he gets lost. He meets new friends on the way. What movie is this?",  "ans" : "Bolt",  "opt1" : "Bambi",  "opt2" : "Air Buddies",  "opt3" : "Beverly Hills Chihuahua"},
									{"question": "This is about a baby elephant, with huge ears. This elephant works at a circus, and all the other elephants make fun of him. What movie is this?",  "ans" : "Dumbo",  "opt1" : "Lady and the Tramp",  "opt2" : "Bambi",  "opt3" : "Alice in Wonderland"},
									{"question": "This movie is about lots of puppies. They are all a particular type of breed with spots and an evil lady, called Cruella Deville, tries to capture them. What is this movie?",  "ans" : "101 Dalmatians",  "opt1" : "Underdog",  "opt2" : "The Fox and the Hound",  "opt3" : "Air Buddies"},
									{"question": "Who was the biggest selling female artist in America in the 1990s?",  "ans" : "Mariah Carey",  "opt1" : "Britanny Spears",  "opt2" : "Celine Dion",  "opt3" : "Shakira"},
									{"question": "This movie is about a man trying to fly his house to Paradise Falls. He flies his house by using balloons and is accompanied by a boy called Russell. What movie is this?",  "ans" : "Up",  "opt1" : "G-force",  "opt2" : "Mulan",  "opt3" : "Enchanted"},
									{"question": "This movie is a remake of a fairytale. It is about a prince who has turned into a frog, and he needs a princess to kiss him, to change back. But she ends up turning into a frog too! What movie is this?",  "ans" : "The Princess and the Frog",  "opt1" : "Cinderella",  "opt2" : "Enchanted",  "opt3" : "The Frog Prince"},
									{"question": "This movie isnt a cartoon and it is kind of old. It is about a mother and her daughter, who switch bodies for a while, and have to live different lives. Do you know what movie this could be?",  "ans" : "Freaky Friday",  "opt1" : "Tricky Tuesday",  "opt2" : "Switchy Saturday",  "opt3" : "Wacky Wednesday"},
									{"question": "I am a Polish born composer and performer of beautiful haunting melodies from the romantic era in music. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Chopin",  "opt1" : "Mozart",  "opt2" : "Beethoven",  "opt3" : "Mendelssohn"},
									{"question": "I am an American actor, scriptwriter and director, known mostly for my work in television, and perhaps most particularly for a series in which I worked with fellow actor Bill Cosby. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Robert Culp",  "opt1" : "Brad Pitt",  "opt2" : "Don Adams",  "opt3" : "Robert Vaughan"},
									{"question": "I am an actor known world wide for my role in one of the 'Star Trek' series on television. My Russian accent tends to give me away. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Walter Koenig",  "opt1" : "George Takei",  "opt2" : "William Shatner",  "opt3" : "DeForrest Kelley"},
									{"question": "I am best known perhaps for portraying a Marshall on the TV show 'Gunsmoke' for twenty seasons, and also had a successful career in films as well. Who am I?",  "ans" : "James Arness",  "opt1" : "William Fairbanks",  "opt2" : "Roy Rogers",  "opt3" : "George Seaton"},
									{"question": "I am a film actor known for my ongoing role in a television spy series. In this series I cost a whole lot of money to repair and maintain because of my special robotic implants. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Lee Majors",  "opt1" : "Robert Culp",  "opt2" : "Alan Alda",  "opt3" : "Leonard Nimoy"},
									{"question": "I am an American composer, conductor and pianist, known for my work on Broadway - particularly on the west side. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Leonard Bernstein",  "opt1" : "Glenn Gould",  "opt2" : "Aaron Copeland",  "opt3" : "Gustav Mahler"},
									{"question": "I am a German composer who lived from 1685 to 1750, but during my lifetime I was most famous for my performances as an organist. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Puccini",  "opt1" : "Bach",  "opt2" : "Chopin",  "opt3" : "Dvorak"},
									{"question": "I am a world famous baseball player, radio and film star - and a bit of a baby. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Babe Ruth",  "opt1" : "Jackie Robinson",  "opt2" : "Larry Doby",  "opt3" : "Roger Maris"},
									{"question": "I am a blonde American actress known for e-mailing and French kissing. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Meg Ryan",  "opt1" : "Marilyn Monroe",  "opt2" : "Betty Grable",  "opt3" : "Jayne Mansfield"},
									{"question": "I am a famous actress of many award winning movies. Im a bit of a mamma mia from out of Africa. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Meryl Streep",  "opt1" : "Joan Crawford",  "opt2" : "Katherine Hepburn",  "opt3" : "Grace Kelly"},
									{"question": "Who played both Vinnie Barbarino and Vincent Vega?",  "ans" : "John Travolta",  "opt1" : "Johnny Depp",  "opt2" : "Christian Slater",  "opt3" : "Samuel L. Jackson"},
									{"question": "Which star appeared as Luke Brower and Howard Hughes?",  "ans" : "Leonardo DiCaprio",  "opt1" : "Paul Le Mat",  "opt2" : "Kirk Cameron",  "opt3" : "Richard Dreyfuss"},
									{"question": "Which popular actor assayed the roles of Dr. Doug Ross beginning in 1994, and Michael Clayton in 2007?",  "ans" : "George Clooney",  "opt1" : "Denzel Washington",  "opt2" : "John Goodman",  "opt3" : "Anthony Edwards"},
									{"question": "Who had an early role on television as Sister Bertrille, and later played Mrs. Gump in a 1994 film?",  "ans" : "Sally Field",  "opt1" : "Tuesday Weld",  "opt2" : "Patty Duke",  "opt3" : "Patricia McCormack"},
									{"question": "Who played Jessica Fletcher on TV and Mrs. Potts in the movies?",  "ans" : "Angela Lansbury",  "opt1" : "Anne Francis",  "opt2" : "Betty White",  "opt3" : "Cloris Leachman"},
									{"question": "Who was Angela Channing on the prime time soap opera 'Falcon Crest' (1981), and won a Best Actress Oscar in 1948 playing a mute named Belinda McDonald?",  "ans" : "Jane Wyman",  "opt1" : "Barbara Bel Geddes",  "opt2" : "Jane Wyatt",  "opt3" : "Donna Reed"},
									{"question": "Who portrayed Josh Randall in the early western TV show 'Wanted Dead or Alive' (1958), and played Henri Charriere in 'Papillon' (1973)?",  "ans" : "Steve McQueen",  "opt1" : "Fred MacMurray",  "opt2" : "James Garner",  "opt3" : "Jack Lemmon"},
									{"question": "Which actor starred as Milton Armitage on TV (1959-1960), and football quarterback Joe Pendelton in a 1978 film?",  "ans" : "Warren Beatty",  "opt1" : "Dennis Quaid",  "opt2" : "Walter Brennan",  "opt3" : "Dustin Hoffman"},
									{"question": "Who was Abbey Bartlet, the presidents wife on 'The West Wing', and also played Betty Rizzo in 'Grease' (1978)?",  "ans" : "Stockard Channing",  "opt1" : "Sandra Dee",  "opt2" : "Susan Sarandon",  "opt3" : "Carol Channing"},
									{"question": "Who played both Michaela Quinn on TV, and Kathleen Cleary in the 2005 movie 'Wedding Crashers'?",  "ans" : "Jane Seymour",  "opt1" : "Jane Fonda",  "opt2" : "Jacqueline Bisset",  "opt3" : "Genevieve Bujold"},
									{"question": "Jim Hawkins is a young boy on a ship named 'The Hispaniola' in which novel?",  "ans" : "Treasure Island",  "opt1" : "Kidnapped",  "opt2" : "Pirates of Penzance",  "opt3" : "Old Man and the Sea"},
									{"question": "Billy Budd was the title character in a novel by whom?",  "ans" : "Herman Melville",  "opt1" : "Ralph Waldo Emerson",  "opt2" : "Walt Whitman",  "opt3" : "Samuel Taylor Coleridge"},
									{"question": "What was the name of the main character in Stephen Kings novel 'The Shining'?",  "ans" : "Jack Torrance",  "opt1" : "John Trent",  "opt2" : "Joe Temple",  "opt3" : "Jake Turpin"},
									{"question": "Oliver Mellors plays the main characters lover in which famous book?",  "ans" : "Lady Chatterlys Lover",  "opt1" : "Women in Love",  "opt2" : "Sons and Lovers",  "opt3" : "The Rainbow"},
									{"question": "What is the name of the spy created by author Len Deighton, according to the movie version of 'The Ipcress File'?",  "ans" : "Harry Palmer",  "opt1" : "Arthur Broughm",  "opt2" : "Henry Axton",  "opt3" : "Alfred Sims"},
									{"question": "Who was the protagonist in Ayn Rands novel 'The Fountainhead'?",  "ans" : "Howard Roark",  "opt1" : "Peter Keating",  "opt2" : "Gail Wynand",  "opt3" : "Ellsworth Toohey"},
									{"question": "Who was the self-sacrificing barrister in Dickens 'A Tale of Two Cities'?",  "ans" : "Sydney Carton",  "opt1" : "Jarvis Lorry",  "opt2" : "Charles Darnay",  "opt3" : "Jerry Cruncher"},
									{"question": "The tragic story of Lenny Small and George Milton can be found in which Steinbeck novel?",  "ans" : "Of Mice and Men",  "opt1" : "East of Eden",  "opt2" : "Cannery Row",  "opt3" : "The Grapes of Wrath"},
									{"question": "Which character is the main focus of 'The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy' by Douglas Adams?",  "ans" : "Arthur Dent",  "opt1" : "R. Daneel Olivaw",  "opt2" : "Elijah Baley",  "opt3" : "Kelden Amadiro"},
									{"question": "What is the name of the old man in Hemingways 'Old Man and the Sea'?",  "ans" : "Santiago",  "opt1" : "Sebastian",  "opt2" : "Rodrigo",  "opt3" : "Antonio"},
									{"question": "This English actress passed away due to a head injury from skiing in 2009. She was in films such as 'The Parent Trap' (1998) and  'Maid in Manhattan' (2002). Who was this actress?",  "ans" : "Natasha Richardson",  "opt1" : "Jennifer Lopez",  "opt2" : "Lisa Ann Walter",  "opt3" : "Elaine Hendrix"},
									{"question": "This comedian was of Colombian descent, went to Columbia University and Harvard Law, and his comedy CDs included 'Midlife Vices' and 'A Good Day to Cross a River'.He died of an accidental prescription overdose in 2010. Who was this?",  "ans" : "Greg Giraldo",  "opt1" : "Mitch Hedberg",  "opt2" : "George Carlin",  "opt3" : "Richard Pryor"},
									{"question": "This author died of throat cancer on November 4th, 2008. He was known for writing many novels which later became movies, such as the 'Jurassic Park' series, 'Sphere', 'The Andromeda Strain' and 'Congo'.  Who was this author?",  "ans" : "Michael Crichton",  "opt1" : "Stephen King",  "opt2" : "George Carlin",  "opt3" : "Dean Koontz"},
									{"question": "This famous actress and sex symbol was on many pinup posters throughout the 1970s. She was also known for her appearance in 'Charlies Angels' as Jill Munroe. She died of cancer.. Who was this actress?",  "ans" : "Farrah Fawcett",  "opt1" : "Marilyn Monroe",  "opt2" : "Anna Nicole Smith",  "opt3" : "Natalie Wood"},
									{"question": "This man was an American journalist and lawyer who was a moderator for the TV show, 'Meet the Press' .  He died on June 13th, 2008  of a heart attack. Who was this journalist?",  "ans" : "Tim Russert",  "opt1" : "Jim Mckay",  "opt2" : "John Zenger",  "opt3" : "John Stewart"},
									{"question": "This actor was born in Australia in 1979 and was in 'Brokeback Mountain' (2005), and 'The Dark Knight' in 2008. He died in 2008  from an accidental combination of prescription drugs. Who was this actor?",  "ans" : "Heath Ledger",  "opt1" : "Mel Gibson",  "opt2" : "Jake Gylenhaall",  "opt3" : "DJ AM"},
									{"question": "He died in  2003 at the age of 100. He was a comedian, entertainer, and a true icon. He was the only person to be considered an honorary veteran of the US Armed Forces. Who was this entertainer?",  "ans" : "Bob Hope",  "opt1" : "Clark Gable",  "opt2" : "Humphrey Bogart",  "opt3" : "Bob Barker"},
									{"question": "This celebrity was a notable actor whose primary works include 'Dirty Dancing' (1987), 'Ghost' (1990). He died of pancreatic cancer on September 14th, 2009. Who was this actor?",  "ans" : "Patrick Swayze",  "opt1" : "Heath Ledger",  "opt2" : "David Hasselhoff",  "opt3" : "Charles Baker"},
									{"question": "My name was Melanie Griffith and I was married four times, twice to the same man. Name this man.",  "ans" : "Don Johnson",  "opt1" : "Steven Bauer",  "opt2" : "Antonio Banderas",  "opt3" : "Richard Gere"},
									{"question": "My name is Suzanne Pleshette and I met my last husband while we were  in 1959 Broadway Comedy 'The Golden Fleecing'. We were married in 2001 and lasted until he passed away. What was his name?",  "ans" : "Tom Poston",  "opt1" : "Peter Bonerz",  "opt2" : "Bob Newhart",  "opt3" : "Peter Scolari"},
									{"question": "My name is Shawn Southwick and I married my husband on September 5, 1997. He had six other wives before me. His real name was Lawrence Harvey Zeiger, but he was known by what name?",  "ans" : "Larry King",  "opt1" : "Geraldo Rivera",  "opt2" : "Maury Povich",  "opt3" : "Jerry Springer"},
									{"question": "Elizabeth Taylor was known for having many husbands. Which one did she marry twice?",  "ans" : "Richard Burton",  "opt1" : "Eddie Fisher",  "opt2" : "Mike Todd",  "opt3" : "John Warner"},
									{"question": "Who was Mickey Rooneys first wife?",  "ans" : "Ava Gardner",  "opt1" : "Judy Garland",  "opt2" : "Lillian Gish",  "opt3" : "Elizabeth Taylor"},
									{"question": "My name is Mia Farrow and when I met my future husband in the mid-sixties, his friend Dean Martin quipped 'I have a bottle of scotch older than her.' Who was my soon-to-be husband?",  "ans" : "Frank Sinatra",  "opt1" : "Woody Allen",  "opt2" : "Peter Lawford",  "opt3" : "Andre Previn"},
									{"question": "The Oscar winning director James Cameron left wife Katherine Bigelow, future Oscar Award winning director of 'The Hurt Locker' (2009), for what actress?",  "ans" : "Linda Hamilton",  "opt1" : "Kate Winslet",  "opt2" : "Gale Anne Hurd",  "opt3" : "Suzy Amis"},
									{"question": "Lee Majors, star of the hit television show 'The Bionic Man' (1974-1978) was married to which angel from the series 'Charlies Angels' (1976-1981)?",  "ans" : "Farrah Fawcett",  "opt1" : "Jaclyn Smith",  "opt2" : "Cheryl Ladd",  "opt3" : "Kate Jackson"},
									{"question": "American music mogul Quincy Jones married which 'Mod Squad' (1968-1973) hippie cop in 1970?",  "ans" : "Farrah Fawcett",  "opt1" : "Linda Evans",  "opt2" : "Jeri Caldwell",  "opt3" : "Susan Dey"},
									{"question": "Uma Thurman was married to which 'Gattaca'(1997) co-star?",  "ans" : "Ethan Hawke",  "opt1" : "Gary Oldman",  "opt2" : "Ryan Phillippe",  "opt3" : "Blair Underwood"},
									{"question": "Which actor played the main villain in 'Code Name: The Cleaner' (2007) as well as the Chairman on 'Iron Chef America' (2005)?",  "ans" : "Mark Dacascos",  "opt1" : "Cedric the Entertainer",  "opt2" : "Bobby Flay",  "opt3" : "Ashley Hamilton"},
									{"question": "Which actress played Jason Lees love interest in 'Mallrats' (2005) and a raven-haired witch, with her two stage sisters, in the first three seasons of 'Charmed' (1998-2001)?",  "ans" : "Shannen Doherty",  "opt1" : "Alyssa Milano",  "opt2" : "Rose McGowan",  "opt3" : "Claire Forlani"},
									{"question": "Which deceased actor from 'Beverly Hills Ninja' got his start on 'Saturday Night Live' performing as a motivational speaker who lived in a van 'circa de los rio', and an unfortunate Japanese game show contestant?",  "ans" : "Chris Farley",  "opt1" : "Michael McDonald",  "opt2" : "Adam Sandler",  "opt3" : "Chris Rock"},
									{"question": "Which controversial daytime talk show host had a cameo appearance in 'Austin Powers: The Spy Who Shagged Me' (1999) and had his own movie titled 'Ringmaster' (1998)?",  "ans" : "Jerry Springer",  "opt1" : "Phil Donahue",  "opt2" : "Mike Myers",  "opt3" : "Geraldo Rivera"},
									{"question": "Which 'Cheers' (1982-1993) star also had a small part as Captain Hamill in Steven Spielbergs war epic 'Saving Private Ryan' (1998)?",  "ans" : "Ted Danson",  "opt1" : "Woody Harrelson",  "opt2" : "Tom Hanks",  "opt3" : "Sean Penn"},
									{"question": "Which actor who played a psychiatrist in 'Cheers' (1982-1993), and other TV shows, starred as an unconventional submarine captain in 'Down Periscope' (1996)?",  "ans" : "Kelsey Grammer",  "opt1" : "John Ratzenberger",  "opt2" : "Rip Torn",  "opt3" : "David Hyde Pierce"},
									{"question": "Which actress got her start in the 1980s dance flicks 'Footloose' (1984)  before landing the starring role in the HBO series 'Sex and the City' ?",  "ans" : "Sarah Jessica Parker",  "opt1" : "Kim Cattrall",  "opt2" : "Cyndi Lauper",  "opt3" : "Lori Singer"},
									{"question": "Which from 'Elf' (2003), 'The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy' (2005), and 'Failure to Launch' (2006) made a guest appearance on her sisters forensic crime-fighting TV show?",  "ans" : "Zooey Deschanel",  "opt1" : "Kathy Bates",  "opt2" : "Mary Steenburgen",  "opt3" : "Michaela Conlin"},
									{"question": "Which Discovery Channel star also worked on the special effects teams for the movie 'Arachnophobia' (1990) and the second two movies in 'The Matrix' trilogy (2003)?",  "ans" : "Jamie Hyneman",  "opt1" : "Mike Rowe",  "opt2" : "Adam Savage",  "opt3" : "Jonathan Hilstrand"},
									{"question": "What was the birth name of American actress Ginger Rogers?",  "ans" : "Virginia McMath",  "opt1" : "Carolina Rogers",  "opt2" : "Elizabeth York",  "opt3" : "Ginger Washington"},
									{"question": "This magicial was most sucessful and holds 11 Guinness World Records. Who is this?",  "ans" : "David Copperfield",  "opt1" : "Howard Cosell",  "opt2" : "Myron Cohen",  "opt3" : "Rodney Dangerfield"},
									{"question": "This actress in 1974 won a Golden Globe for Best Motion Picture Actress in a Musical or Comedy for The Three Musketeers. Who is this?",  "ans" : "Raquel Welch",  "opt1" : "Alan Alda",  "opt2" : "Anne Bancroft",  "opt3" : "Bobby Darin"},
									{"question": "He has won the Academy Award for Best Actor twice, for One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest and for As Good as It Gets. Who is this",  "ans" : "Jack Nicholson",  "opt1" : "June Allyson",  "opt2" : "Randolph Scott",  "opt3" : "Richard Burton"},
									{"question": "He won the Academy Award for Best Director for Schindlers List. Who is this ?",  "ans" : "Spielberg",  "opt1" : "Bono",  "opt2" : "Prince",  "opt3" : "Sinbad"},
									{"question": "One of the four celebrities listed below was *not* born with the surname of Johnson. Who was it?",  "ans" : "Barbara Stanwyck",  "opt1" : "Troy Donahue",  "opt2" : "Whoopi Goldberg",  "opt3" : "Diahann Carroll"},
									{"question": "What was the birth name of horror film actor Boris Karloff?",  "ans" : "William Pratt",  "opt1" : "Wolfgang Peterson",  "opt2" : "Karl Offenberg",  "opt3" : "Roland Karlsberg"},
									{"question": "What is the birth name of pop singer and pianist Barry Manilow?",  "ans" : "Barry Pincus",  "opt1" : "Barry Molinsky",  "opt2" : "Barry Parks",  "opt3" : "Barry Hovick"},
									{"question": "Who played Farrah Fawcett and Chevy Chases son in the 1995 movie 'Man of the House'?",  "ans" : "Jonathan Taylor Thomas",  "opt1" : "Scott Wolf",  "opt2" : "Andrew Keegan",  "opt3" : "Zachery Ty Bryan"},
									{"question": "Who was nominated twice for a Golden Globe for Best Performance by an Actor in a TV Series? (Golden Globes nominations 1993 and 1995)",  "ans" : "Jason Priestley",  "opt1" : "Luke Perry",  "opt2" : "Leonardo DiCaprio",  "opt3" : "Joshua Jackson"},
									{"question": "Which Jive Records sensation started in 1993 but didnt release an album in the United States until 1997?",  "ans" : "Backstreet Boys",  "opt1" : "NSYNC",  "opt2" : "Hanson",  "opt3" : "No Doubt"},
									{"question": "Which one of the following television shows did Jonathan Brandis star in?",  "ans" : "SeaQuest DSV",  "opt1" : "Space Precinct",  "opt2" : "Brotherly Love",  "opt3" : "Party of Five"},
									{"question": "Which Bayside schemer also made an appearance on 'Blossom' and 'Charles in Charge'?",  "ans" : "Mark Paul Gosselaar",  "opt1" : "Lark Voorhies",  "opt2" : "Mario Lopez",  "opt3" : "Tiffani Amber Thiessen"},
									{"question": "Who played Sandy Ricks in the 1996 release of 'Flipper'?",  "ans" : "Elijah Wood",  "opt1" : "Edward Furlong",  "opt2" : "Macaulay Culkin",  "opt3" : "Jonathan Jackson"},
									{"question": "What is the name of the actress whose on-screen character married Cory Matthews in the series 'Boy Meets World'?",  "ans" : "Danielle Fishel",  "opt1" : "Candace Cameron",  "opt2" : "Thora Birch",  "opt3" : "Larisa Oleynik"},
									{"question": "Who played Casper as a real boy in the live-action film 'Casper' (1995)?",  "ans" : "Devon Sawa",  "opt1" : "Josh Hartnett",  "opt2" : "Brad Renfro",  "opt3" : "Jonathan Jackson"},
									{"question": "Often imitated, never duplicated... this heartthrob inspired a national catchphrase. 'Whoa!' Who is he?",  "ans" : "Joey Lawrence",  "opt1" : "Will Smith",  "opt2" : "Johnny Depp",  "opt3" : "Rider Strong"},
									{"question": "This American recording artist and entertainer born in Mississippi made it big with the album ...Baby One More Time. Who is this?",  "ans" : "Britney Spears",  "opt1" : "Jared Leto",  "opt2" : "Katie Holmes",  "opt3" : "Jodi Sweetin"},
									{"question": "This larger-than-life Canadian comedian died in 1994, but before he did he gave us such great characters as Dewey Oxberger (in 'Stripes') and Barf the Mawg (half-man, half-dog) in 'Spaceballs'. Who was he?",  "ans" : "John Candy",  "opt1" : "Lenny Bruce",  "opt2" : "George Carlin",  "opt3" : "Henny Youngman"},
									{"question": "This English model with a funny name was born Lesley Hornby in 1949, and in 1966 Mattel released a doll named for her. Who is this model who took the world by storm when she was a teenager?",  "ans" : "Twiggy",  "opt1" : "Sade",  "opt2" : "Ultra Violet",  "opt3" : "Iman"},
									{"question": "Prince, in 1979, released a song called 'I Feel For You' on his 'Prince' album. Five years later, it became a bigger hit for which rhythm and blues singer?",  "ans" : "Chaka Khan",  "opt1" : "Apollonia 6",  "opt2" : "Sheila E.",  "opt3" : "Morris Day"},
									{"question": "In 1998, this vintner and ufologist was made a Member of the Order of Canada--but hes better-known for playing a Ghostbuster, Doctor Detroit and Sgt. Joe Friday. Who is he?",  "ans" : "Dan Aykroyd",  "opt1" : " Bill Murray",  "opt2" : "Harold Ramis",  "opt3" : "Jack Webb"},
									{"question": "In 2009, this country produced a total of 2961 films. Which country produces the maximum number of movies in a year?",  "ans" : "India",  "opt1" : "USA",  "opt2" : "China",  "opt3" : "Russia"}
        ],
        "Geography": [
									
									{"question": "Its is the world's second largest desert, after Antarctica. This deserts name means 'desert' in Arabic. Name the desert.",  "ans" : "Sahara",  "opt1" : "Thar",  "opt2" : "Gobi",  "opt3" : "Colorado"},
									{"question": "Its is the world's second driest desert, after Antarctica. Most areas only receive moisture from an occasional fog every few decades. Name this desert in Chile?",  "ans" : "Atacama",  "opt1" : "Thar",  "opt2" : "Gobi",  "opt3" : "Colorado"},
									{"question": "Which is the Largest Desert in the World?",  "ans" : "Antartica",  "opt1" : "Sahara",  "opt2" : "Thar",  "opt3" : "Gobi"},
									{"question": "At the higher regions of Mount Everest, climbers seeking the summit typically spend substantial time within the 'death zone' and face significant challenges to survival. Above what altitude in meters does death zone start?",  "ans" : "8000",  "opt1" : "7000",  "opt2" : "9000",  "opt3" : "6000"},
									{"question": "Which is the second-highest mountain on Earth, after Mount Everest. With a peak elevation of 8,611 m (28,251 feet), its a part of the Karakoram Range.",  "ans" : "K2",  "opt1" : "Himalayas",  "opt2" : "Nanga Parbat",  "opt3" : "Kilimanjaro"},
									{"question": "Which river is regarded as the longest river in the world? It is 6,650 km (4,130 miles) long. It runs through nine countries.",  "ans" : "Nile",  "opt1" : "Ganges",  "opt2" : "Danube",  "opt3" : "Thames"},
									{"question": "Geography (from Greek) is the science that deals with the study of the Earth and its lands, features, inhabitants, and phenomena.Who was the first person to use the word 'geography'?",  "ans" : "Eratosthenes",  "opt1" : "Columbus",  "opt2" : "Newton",  "opt3" : "Copernicus"},
									{"question": "The Alexander Archipelago is part of which state in the US?",  "ans" : "Alaska",  "opt1" : "British Columbia",  "opt2" : "Washington State",  "opt3" : "Oregon"},
									{"question": "The Ligurian Sea is off the coast of which country?",  "ans" : "Italy",  "opt1" : "France",  "opt2" : "Britain",  "opt3" : "Spain"},
									{"question": "Prior to independence, East Timor was part of which country?",  "ans" : "Indonesia",  "opt1" : "Philippines",  "opt2" : "Serbia",  "opt3" : "Malaysia"},
									{"question": "Stalactite and Stalagmite are made up of what materials?",  "ans" : "Limestone",  "opt1" : "Copper",  "opt2" : "Granite",  "opt3" : "Wood"},
									{"question": "What are Coral Reefs made up of?",  "ans" : "Calcium Carbonate",  "opt1" : "LimeStone",  "opt2" : "Salt",  "opt3" : "Sea Weeds"},
									{"question": "Bermuda Triangle is a region in the Ocean where a number of aircraft and surface vessels allegedly disappeared under mysterious circumstances. What is another Name for this?",  "ans" : "Devils Triangle",  "opt1" : "Atlantic Triangle",  "opt2" : "Pacific Triangle",  "opt3" : "Caribbean Triangle"},
									{"question": "First successful ascent of Everest was by a New Zealander and Tenzing Norgay, a Nepali sherpa. What was the name of the New Zealander?",  "ans" : "Edmund Hillary",  "opt1" : "Neil Armstrong",  "opt2" : "Yuri Gagarin",  "opt3" : "John Hunt"},
									{"question": "What is the largest city in the US named after a British PM?",  "ans" : "Pittsburg",  "opt1" : "NewYork",  "opt2" : "Washington",  "opt3" : "Atlanta"},
									{"question": "With 4,400 km, what is the longest river in the world beginning with the letter 'L'?",  "ans" : "Lena",  "opt1" : "Laman",  "opt2" : "Lane",  "opt3" : "Lester"},
									{"question": "Which popular dried fruit is named after a port city in Greece?",  "ans" : "Corinthians",  "opt1" : "Athens",  "opt2" : "Voros",  "opt3" : "Serres"},
									{"question": "What is Stalingrad called today?",  "ans" : "Volgograd",  "opt1" : "Moscow",  "opt2" : "Lagan",  "opt3" : "Luga"},
									{"question": "In which US state did the Battle of Little Big Horn take place?",  "ans" : "Montana",  "opt1" : "Washington",  "opt2" : "California",  "opt3" : "Georgia"},
									{"question": "The ghost town Pripyat is found in which country?",  "ans" : "Ukraine",  "opt1" : "Russia",  "opt2" : "Germany",  "opt3" : "France"},
									{"question": "According to UNICEF, which African country has the most land mines in the world?",  "ans" : "Egypt",  "opt1" : "Israel",  "opt2" : "Zambia",  "opt3" : "Srilanka"},
									{"question": "The Althing, the world's oldest surviving parliament, is found in which country?",  "ans" : "Iceland",  "opt1" : "Greece",  "opt2" : "Italy",  "opt3" : "Britain"},
									{"question": "How many time zones are there in China?",  "ans" : "One",  "opt1" : "Two",  "opt2" : "Three",  "opt3" : "Four"},
									{"question": "Which tiny island country did Columbus discover on a Sunday?",  "ans" : "Dominica",  "opt1" : "Philippines",  "opt2" : "Jamica",  "opt3" : "Guyana"},
									{"question": "The name of which river or band translated means 'hated'?",  "ans" : "Styx",  "opt1" : "Nile",  "opt2" : "Amazon",  "opt3" : "Congo"},
									{"question": "There are 20 regions in Italy. Which region is the toe of Italy?",  "ans" : "Calabria",  "opt1" : "Lombardy",  "opt2" : "Tuscany",  "opt3" : "Lombardy"},
									{"question": "Formerly the 'British protectorate of Bechuanaland', which republic adopted its new name after becoming independent within the Commonwealth on the 30th September 1966?",  "ans" : "Botswana",  "opt1" : "India",  "opt2" : "Canada",  "opt3" : "Australia"},
									{"question": "Which European country has the most lakes?",  "ans" : "Russia",  "opt1" : "Finland",  "opt2" : "Canada",  "opt3" : "Australia"},
									{"question": "The Komodo National Park is famous for its Komodo Dragons. In which country is this park found?",  "ans" : "Indonesia",  "opt1" : "Thailand",  "opt2" : "China",  "opt3" : "Japan"},
									{"question": "Which country with a land mass of 9.6 million square kilometres has just one time zone?",  "ans" : "China",  "opt1" : "India",  "opt2" : "Russia",  "opt3" : "Australia"},
									{"question": "Which river flows through  Germany, Austria , Slovakia, Hungary, Croatia, Serbia, Bulgaria, Moldova , Ukraine  and Romania?",  "ans" : "Danube",  "opt1" : "Thames",  "opt2" : "Volga",  "opt3" : "Rhine"},
									{"question": "Name the European Union county that has the most borders with other countries.",  "ans" : "Germany",  "opt1" : "England",  "opt2" : "France",  "opt3" : "Spain"},
									{"question": "Saudi Arabia is one country in the world beginning with the letter 'S' that have a sword or a saber on the national flag. What is the name of the other Asian country?",  "ans" : "Srilanka",  "opt1" : "Sweden",  "opt2" : "Slovakia",  "opt3" : "Spain"},
									{"question": "Which is the most populated country in the world?",  "ans" : "China",  "opt1" : "India",  "opt2" : "America",  "opt3" : "Canada"},
									{"question": "In mythology, who ran away with Helen and is the name of a Countries Capital?",  "ans" : "Paris",  "opt1" : "Rome",  "opt2" : "Madrid",  "opt3" : "Berlin"},
									{"question": "Which capital city is also a very hot spice used in the kitchen?",  "ans" : "Cayenne",  "opt1" : "Bejing",  "opt2" : "Tokyo",  "opt3" : "Delhi"},
									{"question": "Which capital city is also the name of an historical duke?",  "ans" : "Wellington",  "opt1" : "Auckland",  "opt2" : "Sydney",  "opt3" : "Brisbane"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Belgium?",  "ans" : "Brussels",  "opt1" : "Antwerp",  "opt2" : "Mons",  "opt3" : "Ghent"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Colombia?",  "ans" : "Bogota",  "opt1" : "Soledad",  "opt2" : "Neiva",  "opt3" : "Cali"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of China?",  "ans" : "Beijing",  "opt1" : "Shangai",  "opt2" : "Taipei",  "opt3" : "Jakarta"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Switzerland?",  "ans" : "Berne",  "opt1" : "Antwerp",  "opt2" : "Zurich",  "opt3" : "Geneva"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Lebanon?",  "ans" : "Beirut",  "opt1" : "Tyre",  "opt2" : "Hermel",  "opt3" : "Saida"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Barbados?",  "ans" : "Bridgetown",  "opt1" : "Grenada",  "opt2" : "Crane",  "opt3" : "Tyre"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Hungary?",  "ans" : "Budapest",  "opt1" : "Antwerp",  "opt2" : "Zurich",  "opt3" : "Debrecen"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Belize?",  "ans" : "Belmopan",  "opt1" : "Tyre",  "opt2" : "Hermel",  "opt3" : "Saida"},
									{"question": "What is the Capital of Mali?",  "ans" : "Bamako",  "opt1" : "Belmopan",  "opt2" : "Tyre",  "opt3" : "Hermel"},
									{"question": "Luanda is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Angola",  "opt1" : "Belmopan",  "opt2" : "Tyre",  "opt3" : "Hermel"},
									{"question": "Gaborone is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Botswana",  "opt1" : "Kano",  "opt2" : "Tripoli",  "opt3" : "Accra"},
									{"question": "Bujumbura is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Burundi",  "opt1" : "Angola",  "opt2" : "Belmopan",  "opt3" : "Tyre"},
									{"question": "Dar es Salaam is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Tanzania",  "opt1" : "Botswana",  "opt2" : "Kano",  "opt3" : "Tripoli"},
									{"question": "Cairo is the Capital of ?",  "ans" : "Egypt",  "opt1" : "Tanzania",  "opt2" : "Botswana",  "opt3" : "Kano"},
									{"question": "Bamako is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Mali",  "opt1" : "Angola",  "opt2" : "Belmopan",  "opt3" : "Tyre"},
									{"question": "Accra is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Ghana",  "opt1" : "Tanzania",  "opt2" : "Botswana",  "opt3" : "Kano"},
									{"question": "Maputo is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Mozambique",  "opt1" : "Ghana",  "opt2" : "Tanzania",  "opt3" : "Botswana"},
									{"question": "Rabat is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Morocco",  "opt1" : "Mozambique",  "opt2" : "Ghana",  "opt3" : "Tanzania"},
									{"question": "Kampala is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Uganda",  "opt1" : "Morocco",  "opt2" : "Mozambique",  "opt3" : "Ghana"},
									{"question": "Nairobi is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Kenya",  "opt1" : "Uganda",  "opt2" : "Morocco",  "opt3" : "Mozambique"},
									{"question": "Victoria is the Capital of?",  "ans" : "Seychelles",  "opt1" : "Brussels",  "opt2" : "Antwerp",  "opt3" : "Mons"},
									{"question": "How many US states have the word new in their name?",  "ans" : "4",  "opt1" : "6",  "opt2" : "3",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "Which is the oldest and largest national park in the USA?",  "ans" : "Yellowstone",  "opt1" : "Ranier",  "opt2" : "Shenandoah",  "opt3" : "Yosemite "},
									{"question": "Before it was bought by America to which country did Alaska belong?",  "ans" : "Russia",  "opt1" : "Canada",  "opt2" : "Mexico",  "opt3" : "Japan"},
									{"question": "In which cemetery just outside of Washington DC have soldiers been buried since the civil war?",  "ans" : "Arlington",  "opt1" : "Vermont",  "opt2" : "Virginia",  "opt3" : "Richmond"},
									{"question": "Which US state is rectangular?",  "ans" : "Colorado",  "opt1" : "Texas",  "opt2" : "Georgia",  "opt3" : "Connecticut"},
									{"question": "Which valley in California is world famous for its wine making?",  "ans" : "Napa",  "opt1" : "Fresno",  "opt2" : "Sacremento",  "opt3" : "Oakland"},
									{"question": "Which famous university is located in Cambridge Massachusetts?",  "ans" : "Harvard",  "opt1" : "Brown",  "opt2" : "Princeton",  "opt3" : "Yale"},
									{"question": "Out of the 20 highest mountains in America, 17 are in which state?",  "ans" : "Alaska",  "opt1" : "Washington",  "opt2" : "California",  "opt3" : "Massachusetts"},
									{"question": "What is the official language of Liechtenstein?",  "ans" : "German",  "opt1" : "French",  "opt2" : "English",  "opt3" : "Spanish"},
									{"question": "What is Scotland's longest river?",  "ans" : "Tay",  "opt1" : "Laman",  "opt2" : "Lane",  "opt3" : "Thames"},
									{"question": "Which famous European building has a name meaning Citadel?",  "ans" : "Kremlin",  "opt1" : "Eiffel",  "opt2" : "Acropolis",  "opt3" : "Stonehenge"},
									{"question": "In which county is Leamington Spa?",  "ans" : "Warwickshire",  "opt1" : "Berkshire",  "opt2" : "Durham",  "opt3" : "Essex"},
									{"question": "Which is the most Northerly capital city on the European continent?",  "ans" : "Helsinki",  "opt1" : "Oslo",  "opt2" : "Stockholm",  "opt3" : "London"},
									{"question": "What mountain lies between the Rhine and Rhone river?",  "ans" : "Jura",  "opt1" : "Alps",  "opt2" : "Lebenon",  "opt3" : "Caucasus"},
									{"question": "Which Hungarian city was formed from 2 towns on opposite sides of the Danube?",  "ans" : "Budapest",  "opt1" : "Antwerp",  "opt2" : "Zurich",  "opt3" : "Geneva"},
									{"question": "What became the 50th state of the USA?",  "ans" : "Hawaii",  "opt1" : "Texas",  "opt2" : "Hawaii",  "opt3" : "Georgia"},
									{"question": "Of which former Yugoslavian republic is Zagreb the capital?",  "ans" : "Croatia",  "opt1" : "Slovakia",  "opt2" : "Yugoslavia",  "opt3" : "Crotia"},
									{"question": "In which country would you find the Tyrol?",  "ans" : "Austria",  "opt1" : "Germany",  "opt2" : "France",  "opt3" : "Italy"},
									{"question": "In which Polish city was the union Solidarity formed in 1980?",  "ans" : "Gdansk",  "opt1" : "Paris",  "opt2" : "Warsaw",  "opt3" : " Budapest"},
									{"question": "Which countries are divided by the Kattegat sea passage and starts with the letter S?",  "ans" : "Sweden",  "opt1" : "Switzerland",  "opt2" : "Spain",  "opt3" : "Serbia"},
									{"question": "Name the mountainous peninsula on the Macedonian coast of Greece?",  "ans" : "Athos",  "opt1" : "Jura",  "opt2" : "Alps",  "opt3" : "Lebenon"},
									{"question": "Which European town gave its name to a treaty that symbolises closer economic links between European countries?",  "ans" : "Maastricht",  "opt1" : "Paris",  "opt2" : "Rome",  "opt3" : "Jura"},
									{"question": "Founded in 1908 what is the oldest university in northern Ireland called?",  "ans" : "Queens",  "opt1" : "Dublin",  "opt2" : "Cork",  "opt3" : "Galway"},
									{"question": "In which European country do Sabena airlines hail from?",  "ans" : "Belgium",  "opt1" : "France",  "opt2" : "Germany",  "opt3" : "Spain"},
									{"question": "Which country lies to the north of Austria and the south of Poland?",  "ans" : "Czech",  "opt1" : "Romania",  "opt2" : "Germany",  "opt3" : "Netherlands"},
									{"question": "On which sea does Croatia stand?",  "ans" : "Adriatic",  "opt1" : "Black",  "opt2" : "Caspian",  "opt3" : "Dead"},
									{"question": "In which country was the Angel of the North erected in 1998?",  "ans" : "England",  "opt1" : "Paris",  "opt2" : "Wimbledon",  "opt3" : "Rome"},
									{"question": "Atomium is a monument with tubes that connect the spheres. They enclose escalators connecting the spheres. In which European city is the Atomium?",  "ans" : "Brussels",  "opt1" : "Paris",  "opt2" : "London",  "opt3" : "Rome"},
									{"question": "The Simplon tunnel links Italy to which other country?",  "ans" : "Switzerland",  "opt1" : "France",  "opt2" : "Greece",  "opt3" : "Spain"},
									{"question": "What was the well-known former name of Iran?",  "ans" : "Persia",  "opt1" : "Arabia",  "opt2" : "Hindustan",  "opt3" : "Babylon "},
									{"question": "Which country is the worlds largest producer of Tea?",  "ans" : "India",  "opt1" : "Srilanka",  "opt2" : "Columbia",  "opt3" : "Britain"},
									{"question": "What is the capital of Pakistan?",  "ans" : "Islamabad",  "opt1" : "Kabul",  "opt2" : "Karachi",  "opt3" : "Quetta"},
									{"question": "Where did the gang of 4 try to seize power in 1976?",  "ans" : "China",  "opt1" : "Japan",  "opt2" : "Korea",  "opt3" : "Indonesia"},
									{"question": "Which native East-Asian plant is the richest natural vegetable food?",  "ans" : "Soya",  "opt1" : "Spinach",  "opt2" : "Cabbage",  "opt3" : "Carrot"},
									{"question": "The West Bank of which river has been conquered by Israel since 1967?",  "ans" : "Jordan",  "opt1" : "Ayalon",  "opt2" : "Dan",  "opt3" : "Yarkon"},
									{"question": "The ancient trading post of Malacca can be found in which country?",  "ans" : "Malaysia",  "opt1" : "India",  "opt2" : "Indonesia",  "opt3" : "China"},
									{"question": "In which country would you find Manila?",  "ans" : "Philapinnes",  "opt1" : "Indonesia",  "opt2" : "Thailand",  "opt3" : "Korea"},
									{"question": "Name the African capital named after a US President?",  "ans" : "Monrovia",  "opt1" : "Tripoli",  "opt2" : "Liberia",  "opt3" : "Washington"},
									{"question": "Its name means Little Venice. Name the Country?",  "ans" : "Venezuela",  "opt1" : "Columbia",  "opt2" : "Brazil",  "opt3" : "Argentina"},
									{"question": "This ancient place name comes from the Greek word for between the rivers. What is its name?",  "ans" : "Mesopotamia",  "opt1" : "Alexandria",  "opt2" : "Croton",  "opt3" : " Ithaca"},
									{"question": "Its name comes form the Latin phrase for unknown southern land. Name the country?",  "ans" : "Australia",  "opt1" : "New Zealand",  "opt2" : "Greece",  "opt3" : "Italy    "},
									{"question": "Jilin is a province in which Asian Country?",  "ans" : "China",  "opt1" : "India",  "opt2" : "Srilanka",  "opt3" : "Pakistan    "},
									{"question": "Historically was the capital of the Venetian Republic. Its called 'City of Canals'. Which city is this?",  "ans" : "Venice",  "opt1" : "Istanbul",  "opt2" : "London",  "opt3" : "Rome"}
        ],
        "History": [
									
									{"question": "Gandhi pioneered satyagraha, resistance to tyranny through mass civil resistance.His philosophy was firmly founded upon ahimsa (nonviolence).Which decade was he born in?",  "ans" : "1860s",  "opt1" : "1840s",  "opt2" : "1880s",  "opt3" : "1870s"},
									{"question": "September 1888, Gandhi travelled to London, England, to study. What was Gandhi's profession?",  "ans" : "Barrister",  "opt1" : "Doctor",  "opt2" : "Engineer",  "opt3" : "Priest"},
									{"question": "In May 1883, the 13-year old Ghandhi was married to Kasturbai in an arranged child marriage, according to the custom of the region. How many children did they have?",  "ans" : "4",  "opt1" : "5",  "opt2" : "3",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "Gandhi faced the discrimination and was thrown off a train after refusing to move from the first class to a third-class coach while holding a valid first-class ticket. In Which Country did he start his revolt against the British?",  "ans" : "South Africa",  "opt1" : "England",  "opt2" : "India",  "opt3" : "USA"},
									{"question": "In 1857, a war broke out between Britain and China. This was due to the Chinese reluctance to follow the conditions of which treaty?",  "ans" : "Nanking",  "opt1" : "Taipei",  "opt2" : "Beijing",  "opt3" : "Guangzhou"},
									{"question": " Who wrote the book, 'An Autobiography of My Experiments with Truth'?",  "ans" : "Gandhi",  "opt1" : "Nehru",  "opt2" : "Indira",  "opt3" : "Rajiv"},
									{"question": "How many wives did Henry VIII have beheaded?",  "ans" : "2",  "opt1" : "6",  "opt2" : "1",  "opt3" : "4"},
									{"question": "This group of people led by former Confederate army officers, were a secret terrorist organization,known as the what?",  "ans" : "Ku Klux Klan",  "opt1" : "The Terrorists",  "opt2" : "G-Unit",  "opt3" : "Soviet Union"},
									{"question": "In what year did Henry VIII break with the Catholic Church?",  "ans" : "1533",  "opt1" : "1553",  "opt2" : "1547",  "opt3" : "1509"},
									{"question": "What was the name of the Minister-President of Prussia during the Schleswig-Holstein affair who ultimately gained the Duchies for Prussia and Austria?",  "ans" : "Bismarck",  "opt1" : "Lusitania",  "opt2" : "Leopold",  "opt3" : "Talleyrand"},
									{"question": "In the 19th century , Isabella, the child queen of Spain, married which duke?",  "ans" : "Duke of Cadiz",  "opt1" : "Duke of Seville",  "opt2" : "Duke of Zaragoza",  "opt3" : "Duke of Madrid"},
									{"question": "There was one year in the 1840s that was referred to as the ' year of revolutions' . The inspiration for many of these European revolutions was a mixture of liberalism and nationalism . What was the year?",  "ans" : "1848",  "opt1" : "1847",  "opt2" : "1846",  "opt3" : "1849"},
									{"question": "1850  Palmerston had to deal with an anti-Semitic attack on a British national in Greece. What was the name of the Jewish merchant that was attacked?",  "ans" : "Don Pacifico",  "opt1" : "Don Indiano",  "opt2" : "Don Atlantico",  "opt3" : "Don Hudsono"},
									{"question": "In 1850s and 1860s Palmerston had to deal with the struggle for Italian unification. Which of the following was an Italian nationalist leader made the  unification process a success?",  "ans" : "Garibaldi",  "opt1" : "Emmanuel",  "opt2" : "Pio Nono",  "opt3" : "Louis Philippe"},
									{"question": "What religion was Queen Mary I?",  "ans" : "Catholic",  "opt1" : "Calvinist",  "opt2" : "Church of England",  "opt3" : "Jewish"},
									{"question": "In what year did Mary I marry Philip II of Spain? ",  "ans" : "1554",  "opt1" : "1558",  "opt2" : "1553",  "opt3" : "1603"},
									{"question": "Mary was called ' Bloody Mary'  because she burned a lot of heretics. Where did most of the burnings take place?",  "ans" : "Smithfield",  "opt1" : "Glasgow",  "opt2" : "Bishop' s Gate",  "opt3" : "Oxford"},
									{"question": "In what year was Elizabeth I excommunicated by the Pope?",  "ans" : "1570",  "opt1" : "1603",  "opt2" : "1553",  "opt3" : "1922"},
									{"question": "Who dealt with the political split with Rome during Henry VIII' s reign after Wolsey died?",  "ans" : "Cromwell",  "opt1" : "Dudley",  "opt2" : "Cranmer",  "opt3" : "Buckingham"},
									{"question": "Who talked Edward VI into changing the order of succession?",  "ans" : "Northumberland",  "opt1" : "Mary",  "opt2" : "Cranmer",  "opt3" : "Buckingham"},
									{"question": "Who was Elizabeth I' s first Secretary of State?",  "ans" : "William Cecil",  "opt1" : "Northumberland",  "opt2" : "Thomas Cromwell",  "opt3" : "Oliver Cromwell"},
									{"question": "In what country did Mary, Queen of Scots grow up?",  "ans" : "France",  "opt1" : "England",  "opt2" : "Scotland",  "opt3" : "Spain"},
									{"question": "What was the name of Mary, Queen of Scots'  secretary who was killed after there were rumours of an affair?",  "ans" : "Riccio",  "opt1" : "Buckingham",  "opt2" : "Darnley",  "opt3" : "Bothwell"},
									{"question": "Where did Mary, Queen of Scots escape to after her subjects rose up against her?",  "ans" : "England",  "opt1" : "Ireland",  "opt2" : "France",  "opt3" : "Italy"},
									{"question": "Who succeeded Elizabeth as ruler of England?",  "ans" : "James",  "opt1" : "Henry",  "opt2" : "Edward",  "opt3" : "Anne"},
									{"question": "In what year did Elizabeth's successor end the wars with Spain?",  "ans" : "1604",  "opt1" : "1597",  "opt2" : "1632",  "opt3" : "1609"},
									{"question": "In what year did slavery end?",  "ans" : "1865",  "opt1" : "1863",  "opt2" : "1867",  "opt3" : "1869"},
									{"question": "This era was considered the one of the best times in history but also a short lived one,introducing new ways of art,poetry and especially music.",  "ans" : "Harlem Renaissance",  "opt1" : "Black era",  "opt2" : "Civil Rights Movement",  "opt3" : "Jazz Era"},
									{"question": "This famous African American was the author of,'Their Eyes were watching God' ,and ' Dust Tracks on a Road' ?",  "ans" : "Zora Neal Hurston",  "opt1" : "Claude McKay",  "opt2" : "Alex Haley",  "opt3" : "Maya Angelou"},
									{"question": "This famous Baltimore Native was known for her contribution to the music industry with unforgettable songs like 'Them there Eyes' and ' God Bless The Child'",  "ans" : "Billie Holiday",  "opt1" : "Lena Horne",  "opt2" : "Bessie Smith",  "opt3" : "Ethel Waters"},
									{"question": "Arthur Ashe was a famous in which sport?",  "ans" : "Tennis",  "opt1" : "Basketball",  "opt2" : "Golf",  "opt3" : "Astronaut"},
									{"question": "Charles Drew is responsible for which of the following?",  "ans" : "Blood Banks",  "opt1" : "Plastic Surgery",  "opt2" : "Refrigerator",  "opt3" : "Piano"},
									{"question": "Slaves were taken where after being captured?",  "ans" : "Castle",  "opt1" : "Boat",  "opt2" : "Cave",  "opt3" : "Auction"},
									{"question": "Which of the following is considered the birthplace of jazz?",  "ans" : "New Orleans",  "opt1" : "Chicago",  "opt2" : "New York",  "opt3" : "Philly"},
									{"question": "He started the 'Back to Africa Movement',and was later deported back to his homeland in Jamaica.",  "ans" : "Marcus Garvey",  "opt1" : "Albert Johnson",  "opt2" : "Kunta Kente",  "opt3" : "Malcolm X"},
									{"question": "She was the first African American to publish her writings",  "ans" : "Phyllis Wheatly",  "opt1" : "Lynda Jhonson",  "opt2" : "Mae Jemison",  "opt3" : "Sojourner Truth"},
									{"question": "This famous actor starred in Blade and New Jack City.",  "ans" : "Wesley Snipes",  "opt1" : "Omar Gooding",  "opt2" : "Allan Payne",  "opt3" : "Tyler Perry"},
									{"question": "Which of the following promised African Americans their freedom first,if they joined their side at war?",  "ans" : "British",  "opt1" : "London",  "opt2" : "Germany",  "opt3" : "United States"},
									{"question": "Adolf Hitler was born in which country?",  "ans" : "Austria",  "opt1" : "France",  "opt2" : "Germany",  "opt3" : "Hungary"},
									{"question": "John F. Kennedy was assassinated where?",  "ans" : "Dallas",  "opt1" : "Austin",  "opt2" : "Atlanta",  "opt3" : "Washington"},
									{"question": "He officially accepted Japan's surrender on 2 September 1945, and oversaw the occupation of Japan from 1945 to 1951. Which American general famously stated 'I shall return' ?",  "ans" : "Douglas MacArthur",  "opt1" : "Bull Halsey",  "opt2" : "George Patton",  "opt3" : "Omar Bradley"},
									{"question": "American involvement in the Korean War took place in which decade?",  "ans" : "1950s",  "opt1" : "1970s",  "opt2" : "1920s",  "opt3" : "1960s"},
									{"question": "The Battle of Hastings in 1066 was fought in which country?",  "ans" : "England",  "opt1" : "France",  "opt2" : "Russia",  "opt3" : "Norway"},
									{"question": "The Magna Carta was published by the King of which country?",  "ans" : "England",  "opt1" : "France",  "opt2" : "Austria",  "opt3" : "Italy"},
									{"question": "The first successful printing press was developed by this man. Who is this?",  "ans" : "Johannes Gutenburg",  "opt1" : "Benjamin Franklin",  "opt2" : "Sir Isaac Newton",  "opt3" : "Martin Luther"},
									{"question": "The disease that ravaged and killed a third of Europe's population in the 14th century is known as?",  "ans" : "Bubonic Plague",  "opt1" : "White Death",  "opt2" : "Black Plague",  "opt3" : "Smallpox"},
									{"question": "Which Roman Emperor built a massive wall across Northern Britain in 122 A.D.?",  "ans" : "Hadrian",  "opt1" : "Marcus Aurelius",  "opt2" : "Nero",  "opt3" : "Augustus"},
									{"question": "This man wrote a document known as the 95 Theses. Who was he?",  "ans" : "Martin Luther",  "opt1" : "Saint Augustus",  "opt2" : "Henry David Thoreau",  "opt3" : "Voltaire"},
									{"question": "In 1594 William Shakespeare joined the company of this London theatre.What was its name?",  "ans" : "The Globe",  "opt1" : "Broadway",  "opt2" : "Oxford University Theatre",  "opt3" : "The London Palladium"},
									{"question": "The Khmer Rouge was a regime ruling this nation in the 20th century. Name the Country?",  "ans" : "Cambodia",  "opt1" : "Vietnam",  "opt2" : "Laos",  "opt3" : "China"},
									{"question": "What famous 5th century A.D conqueror was known as 'The Scourge of God' ?",  "ans" : "Atilla the Hun",  "opt1" : "Hannibal",  "opt2" : "Julius Caesar",  "opt3" : "William the Conqueror"},
									{"question": "Who was the first Western explorer to reach China?",  "ans" : "Marco Polo",  "opt1" : "Magellan",  "opt2" : "Cook",  "opt3" : "Francis Drake"},
									{"question": "Nov 4th 1995  Yigal Amir murdered whom?",  "ans" : "Yitzak Rabin",  "opt1" : "Benigno Aquino",  "opt2" : "Airey Neave",  "opt3" : "Aldo moro"},
									{"question": "May 21st 1991, in Madras, Tamil terrorists murdered whom?",  "ans" : "Rajiv Gandhi",  "opt1" : "Indira Gandhi",  "opt2" : "Nehru",  "opt3" : "Bhutto"},
									{"question": "Aug 21st 1983 at Manila Airport who was murdered?",  "ans" : "Benigno Aquino",  "opt1" : "Leon Trotsky",  "opt2" : "Spencer Percivel ",  "opt3" : "Airey Neave"},
									{"question": "Oct 6th 1981, who in Cairo was murdered by Muslim Fundamentalists?",  "ans" : "Anwar Sadat",  "opt1" : "Airey Neave",  "opt2" : "Aldo moro",  "opt3" : "Leon Trotsky"},
									{"question": "Mar 30th 1979, who was blown up by the INLA?",  "ans" : "Airey Neave",  "opt1" : "Benigno Aquino",  "opt2" : "Airey Neave",  "opt3" : "Aldo moro"},
									{"question": "May 9th 1978, who did the Red brigade murder?",  "ans" : "Aldo moro",  "opt1" : "Leon Trotsky",  "opt2" : "Spencer Percivel ",  "opt3" : "Airey Neave"},
									{"question": "June 5th 1968 at the Ambassador Hotel Los Angeles who was murdered?",  "ans" : "Robert Kennedy",  "opt1" : "John F Kennedy",  "opt2" : "Lincoln",  "opt3" : "Gandhi"},
									{"question": "Jan 30th 1948 who was murdered by Nathuran Godse in Delhi?",  "ans" : "Gandhi",  "opt1" : "Benigno Aquino",  "opt2" : "Leon Trotsky",  "opt3" : "Spencer Percivel"},
									{"question": "Aug 20th 1940 who was murdered in an ice pick in Mexico city?",  "ans" : "Leon Trotsky",  "opt1" : "Benigno Aquino",  "opt2" : "Airey Neave",  "opt3" : "Aldo moro"},
									{"question": "May 11th 1812, whom did the assassin John bellingham kill?",  "ans" : "Spencer Percivel",  "opt1" : "Benigno Aquino",  "opt2" : "Airey Neave",  "opt3" : "Aldo moro "},
									{"question": "In BC which year did Julius Caesar first visit Britain?",  "ans" : "55",  "opt1" : "70",  "opt2" : "100",  "opt3" : "200"},
									{"question": "Where was Napoleon exiled after his defeat at Waterloo?",  "ans" : "Saint Helena",  "opt1" : "Elba",  "opt2" : "Paris",  "opt3" : "London"},
									{"question": "Which leader of the Huns was known as the 'Scourge of God'?",  "ans" : "Atilla",  "opt1" : "Hannibal",  "opt2" : "Edward",  "opt3" : "Hitler"},
									{"question": "Who first sailed around the Cape of Good Hope?",  "ans" : "Vasco De Gamma",  "opt1" : "Columbus",  "opt2" : "Marco Polo",  "opt3" : "Golden Hind  "},
									{"question": "What phrase was used to describe the German empire under Hitler?",  "ans" : "Third Reich",  "opt1" : "Red Army",  "opt2" : "Khmer Rouge",  "opt3" : "Swastik"},
									{"question": "What new name did Francis Drake give his ship the Pelican during his circumnavigation of the World?",  "ans" : "Golden Hind",  "opt1" : "Atilla",  "opt2" : "Hannibal",  "opt3" : "Edward"},
									{"question": "Which Venetian explorer served the emperor Kublai Khan?",  "ans" : "Marco Polo",  "opt1" : "Magellan",  "opt2" : "Cook",  "opt3" : "Francis Drake"},
									{"question": "Who was in office as President of the United States when the decision was taken to declare war on Germany during World War I?",  "ans" : "Woodrow Wilson",  "opt1" : "Johson",  "opt2" : "Kennedy",  "opt3" : "Lincoln"},
									{"question": "Who was hailed as the founder of the Mongol Empire?",  "ans" : "Genghis Khan",  "opt1" : "Alexander",  "opt2" : "Lincoln",  "opt3" : "Washington"},
									{"question": "Josip Broz led the Communist partisans to victory against foreign occupation forces in Yugoslavia during the Second World War. By what name was he later better known?",  "ans" : "Tito",  "opt1" : "Ivan",  "opt2" : "Hannibal",  "opt3" : "Stalin"},
									{"question": "Who, at the age of forty-three, became the worlds first female President and the youngest Head of State in Latin America in the seventies?",  "ans" : "Isabel Peron",  "opt1" : "Indira Gandhi",  "opt2" : "Isabel Peron",  "opt3" : "Golda Meir"},
									{"question": "Who was the First female Prime Minister of Israel?",  "ans" : "Golda Meir",  "opt1" : "Isabel Peron",  "opt2" : "Indira Gandhi",  "opt3" : "Isabel Peron"},
									{"question": "Which former American President left behind an immortal souvenir -the teddy- which was named after him?",  "ans" : "Roosevelt",  "opt1" : "Lincoln",  "opt2" : "Washinton",  "opt3" : "Kennedy"},
									{"question": "Two men were awarded the Nobel Peace Price in 1993. One was FW de Klerk, who is the Other?",  "ans" : "Mandela",  "opt1" : "Gandhi",  "opt2" : "Nehru",  "opt3" : "Rabin"},
									{"question": "Who was known as the Iron Chancellor?",  "ans" : "Bismarck",  "opt1" : "Hitler",  "opt2" : "Stalin",  "opt3" : "Regan"},
									{"question": "Italian dictator Benito Mussolini had two occupations. One was a Journalist what was the Other?",  "ans" : "Teacher",  "opt1" : "Doctor",  "opt2" : "Tailor",  "opt3" : "Politician"},
									{"question": "He was the son of a Siberian peasant and became the most influential person at the court of Tsar Nicholas II. He was widely thought to have magical powers and was assassinated in 1916. What was his name?",  "ans" : "Rasputi",  "opt1" : "Stalin",  "opt2" : "Putin",  "opt3" : "Hitler"},
									{"question": "In Russia it is also known as the 'Eastern War' and in Britian its know as 'Russian War'. Which war took place between 1853-1856?",  "ans" : "Crimean war",  "opt1" : "Vietnam War",  "opt2" : "Greek Civil War",  "opt3" : "Arab Israeli War"},
									{"question": "Who was the first man to fly the English Channel?",  "ans" : "Louis Bleriot",  "opt1" : "Wright Brothers",  "opt2" : "Newton",  "opt3" : "Edison"},
									{"question": "Which video cassette system, introduced in the 1970s, couldnt compete with the VHS and disappeared?",  "ans" : "Betamax",  "opt1" : "PAL",  "opt2" : "NTSC",  "opt3" : "SONY "},
									{"question": "In which year was President Kennedy assassinated?",  "ans" : "1963",  "opt1" : "1966",  "opt2" : "1959",  "opt3" : "1967"},
									{"question": "In the UK in which decade were l-plates made compulsory for all learner drivers?",  "ans" : "1930s",  "opt1" : "1920s",  "opt2" : "1950s",  "opt3" : "1960s"},
									{"question": "What was the name of company that suffered a severe oil spill in Alaska in 1989?",  "ans" : "Exxon",  "opt1" : "BP",  "opt2" : "Shell",  "opt3" : "Citgo"},
									{"question": "Liverpool airport was renamed in honour of which famous son of the city?",  "ans" : "John Lennon",  "opt1" : "Elton John",  "opt2" : "Boy George",  "opt3" : "Mick Jagger"},
									{"question": "How many wives did Henry VIII have?",  "ans" : "Six",  "opt1" : "Four",  "opt2" : "Three",  "opt3" : "Two"},
									{"question": "Who was the first president of the USA?",  "ans" : "Washington",  "opt1" : "Lincoln",  "opt2" : "Kennedy",  "opt3" : "Nixon"},
									{"question": "The invasion of which country led to the outbreak of World War II?",  "ans" : "Poland",  "opt1" : "Italy",  "opt2" : "France",  "opt3" : "England"},
									{"question": "Which French statesman crowned himself emperor in 1804?",  "ans" : "Napoleon",  "opt1" : "Phillip",  "opt2" : "Charles",  "opt3" : "Louis"},
									{"question": "Who was Spain's dictator until his death in 1975?",  "ans" : "Francisco Franco",  "opt1" : "Juan Carlos",  "opt2" : "Francisco Serrano",  "opt3" : "Joseph Bonaparte"},
									{"question": "Which admiral organised the German navy of World War I?",  "ans" : "Turpitz",  "opt1" : "Hitler",  "opt2" : "Bismark",  "opt3" : "Stalin"},
									{"question": "Which civil rights leader was shot dead in Memphis in 1968?",  "ans" : "Martin Luther King Jr",  "opt1" : "Kennedy",  "opt2" : "Lincoln",  "opt3" : "Washington"},
									{"question": "James Earl Ray was responsible for who's death in 1968?",  "ans" : "Martin Luther King Jr",  "opt1" : "Kennedy",  "opt2" : "Lincoln",  "opt3" : "Washington"},
									{"question": "Who created havoc in 1938, when his radio broadcast of 'The War Of The Worlds' was believed to be true?",  "ans" : "Orson Welles",  "opt1" : "Frank Readick",  "opt2" : "Kenny Delmar",  "opt3" : "Ray Collins  "},
									{"question": "What were Benjy and Laska, which were sent into space in 1958?",  "ans" : "Mice",  "opt1" : "Cat",  "opt2" : "Dog",  "opt3" : "Goat"},
									{"question": "Which American President saw active service in both the first and second World Wars?",  "ans" : "Eisenhower",  "opt1" : "Washington",  "opt2" : "Roosevelt",  "opt3" : "Lincoln"},
									{"question": "He was born in Poland and emigrated to Palestine in 1906. He became the first Prime Minister of the State of Israel. Who was he?",  "ans" : "Ben Gurion",  "opt1" : "Golda Meir",  "opt2" : "Rabin",  "opt3" : "Yasser Arafat"},
									{"question": "The Emancipation Proclamation was an executive order issued during the American Civil War to free the slaves. Who issued it?",  "ans" : "Lincoln",  "opt1" : "Washington",  "opt2" : "Kennedy",  "opt3" : "Nixon"},
									{"question": "World War I began in which year?",  "ans" : "1914",  "opt1" : "1923",  "opt2" : "1938",  "opt3" : "1910"},
									{"question": "What year did the Titanic sink?",  "ans" : "1912",  "opt1" : "1915",  "opt2" : "1918",  "opt3" : "1900"},
									{"question": "Which party did Abraham Lincoln belong to?",  "ans" : "Republican",  "opt1" : "Democrat",  "opt2" : "Libertarian",  "opt3" : "Labour"},
									{"question": "Which party did Franklin Delano Roosevelt belong to?",  "ans" : "Democrat",  "opt1" : "Federalist",  "opt2" : "Republican",  "opt3" : "Libertarian"},
									{"question": "Which party did Dwight David Eisenhower belong to?",  "ans" : "Republican",  "opt1" : "Democrat",  "opt2" : "Libertarian",  "opt3" : "Labour"},
									{"question": "Which party did John Fitzgerald Kennedy belong to?",  "ans" : "Democrat",  "opt1" : "Federalist",  "opt2" : "Republican",  "opt3" : "Libertarian"},
									{"question": "Which party did Lyndon Baines Johnson belong to?",  "ans" : "Democrat",  "opt1" : "Federalist",  "opt2" : "Republican",  "opt3" : "Libertarian"},
									{"question": "Which party did Richard Millhouse Nixon belong to?",  "ans" : "Republican",  "opt1" : "Democrat",  "opt2" : "Libertarian",  "opt3" : "Labour"},
									{"question": "Which party did Gerald Rudolph Ford belong to?",  "ans" : "Republican",  "opt1" : "Democrat",  "opt2" : "Libertarian",  "opt3" : "Labour"},
									{"question": "Which party did James Earl Carter belong to?",  "ans" : "Democrat",  "opt1" : "Federalist",  "opt2" : "Republican",  "opt3" : "Libertarian"},
									{"question": "Which party did Ronald Wilson Reagan belong to?",  "ans" : "Republican",  "opt1" : "Democrat",  "opt2" : "Libertarian",  "opt3" : "Labour"},
									{"question": "Which party did George Washington belong to?",  "ans" : "Federalist",  "opt1" : "Democrat",  "opt2" : "Republican",  "opt3" : "Labour"},
									{"question": "What was the year of the declaration of Independence in America?",  "ans" : "1776",  "opt1" : "1876",  "opt2" : "1666",  "opt3" : "1850"}
        ],
        "Science": [
									{"question": "Which planet in our solar system is named after the Roman god of commerce and thievery?",  "ans" : "Mercury",  "opt1" : "Venus",  "opt2" : "Earth",  "opt3" : "Mars"},
									{"question": "In which 'body of water' are the Islets of Langerhans found?",  "ans" : "Pancreas",  "opt1" : "Liver",  "opt2" : "Kidney",  "opt3" : "Intestine"},
									{"question": "Which scientific word translated means 'disease producer'?",  "ans" : "Pathogen",  "opt1" : "Bacteria",  "opt2" : "Virus",  "opt3" : "Flu"},
									{"question": "What was the name of the German engineer who invented the first rotary engine?",  "ans" : "Wankel",  "opt1" : "Ford",  "opt2" : "Wright",  "opt3" : "Newton"},
									{"question": "What fuel does a Bunsen burner use?",  "ans" : "Gas",  "opt1" : "Petrol",  "opt2" : "Coal",  "opt3" : "Solar"},
									{"question": "Of what is a lux a unit?",  "ans" : "Illumination",  "opt1" : "Thrust",  "opt2" : "Temperature",  "opt3" : "Weight"},
									{"question": "Brent Blend, Tapis, Minas and Midway Sunset Heavy are well-known classifications of what expensive commodity?",  "ans" : "Oil",  "opt1" : "Gas",  "opt2" : "Coal",  "opt3" : "Uranium"},
									{"question": "Ranger, Pioneer, Viking, Galileo and Cassini are some notable examples of what missions?Space",  "ans" : "Navy",  "opt1" : "Artic",  "opt2" : "Antartic",  "opt3" : "Everest"},
									{"question": "Belgrano II, Jinnah, Vostok, McMurdo, Great Wall, Arctowski, Davis and Halley are all examples of what reaseach stations?",  "ans" : "Antarctic",  "opt1" : "Artic",  "opt2" : "Space",  "opt3" : "Agricultural"},
									{"question": "Mars has two moons, one is Deimos can you name the other?",  "ans" : "Phobos",  "opt1" : "Luna",  "opt2" : "Titan",  "opt3" : "Charon"},
									{"question": "How many years does it take Pluto to orbit the sun?",  "ans" : "248",  "opt1" : "300",  "opt2" : "400",  "opt3" : "100"},
									{"question": "Where in the human body is the LUNULA located?",  "ans" : "Fingernail",  "opt1" : "Head",  "opt2" : "Elbow",  "opt3" : "Heart"},
									{"question": "The animal 'Struthio camelus', which can grow to nine feet (2.7 metres) tall, can be trained to successfully herd sheep. What is the more common name of this animal?",  "ans" : "Ostrich",  "opt1" : "Dog",  "opt2" : "Cat",  "opt3" : "Camel"},
									{"question": "Which modern scientific word is Latin for 'amount'?",  "ans" : "Quantum",  "opt1" : "Nucleus",  "opt2" : "Pendo",  "opt3" : "Expendere"},
									{"question": "How many Moons does Jupiter have?",  "ans" : "63",  "opt1" : "55",  "opt2" : "32",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "How many Moons does Saturn have?",  "ans" : "61",  "opt1" : "55",  "opt2" : "32",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "How many Moons does Uranus have?",  "ans" : "27",  "opt1" : "55",  "opt2" : "32",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "How many Moons does Neptune have?",  "ans" : "13",  "opt1" : "55",  "opt2" : "32",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "Pluto has three moons, two are Hydra and Nix, can you name the third?",  "ans" : "Charon",  "opt1" : "Phobos",  "opt2" : "Luna",  "opt3" : "Titan"},
									{"question": "How many Moons does Mercury have?",  "ans" : "0",  "opt1" : "5",  "opt2" : "3",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "How many Moons does Venus have?",  "ans" : "0",  "opt1" : "5",  "opt2" : "3",  "opt3" : "2"},
									{"question": "Which planet is the Closest to the Sun?",  "ans" : "Mercury",  "opt1" : "Venus",  "opt2" : "Earth",  "opt3" : "Pluto"},
									{"question": "The slogan for which famous website is 'We Open Governments'?",  "ans" : "WikiLeaks",  "opt1" : "WikiPedia",  "opt2" : "Google",  "opt3" : "Facebook"},
									{"question": "What name was given to the 3.2 million year old Australopithecus afarensis bones found in Ethiopia in 1974?",  "ans" : "Lucy",  "opt1" : "Omo",  "opt2" : "Sapiens",  "opt3" : "dgyth"},
									{"question": "The scientific name for which animal means 'one who walks swiftly, a camel marked like a leopard'?",  "ans" : "Giraffe",  "opt1" : "Tiger",  "opt2" : "Lion",  "opt3" : "Elephant"},
									{"question": "Toothed and Baleen are both examples of what?",  "ans" : "Whale",  "opt1" : "Shark",  "opt2" : "Dolphins",  "opt3" : "Penguins"},
									{"question": "The Millennium Star, The Centenary, The Red Cross and The Incomparable are all examples of what?",  "ans" : "Diamonds",  "opt1" : "Stars",  "opt2" : "Planets",  "opt3" : "Satellites"},
									{"question": "Which instrument allowed Galileo to make his discovery that the Moon has mountains and craters?",  "ans" : "Telescope",  "opt1" : "Microscope",  "opt2" : "Barometer",  "opt3" : "Spectroscopy"},
									{"question": "Which instrument is used for measuring atmospheric pressure?",  "ans" : "Barometer",  "opt1" : "Thermometer",  "opt2" : "Spectroscope",  "opt3" : "Telescope"},
									{"question": "What technique is often used for identifying substances or for checking their purity?",  "ans" : "Spectroscopy",  "opt1" : "Carbon Dating",  "opt2" : "Microscope",  "opt3" : "Potometer"},
									{"question": "What is Richter scale related to?",  "ans" : "EarthQuake",  "opt1" : "Temperature",  "opt2" : "Pressure",  "opt3" : "Tsunami"},
									{"question": "What is used to measure Earthquakes?",  "ans" : "Seismograph",  "opt1" : "Barometer",  "opt2" : "Spectroscope",  "opt3" : "Microscope"},
									{"question": "What are the Grassland of Northern America Called?",  "ans" : "Prairie",  "opt1" : "Steppe",  "opt2" : "Pampas",  "opt3" : "Gulf"},
									{"question": "Which is the world's largest Ocean?",  "ans" : "Pacific",  "opt1" : "Atlantic",  "opt2" : "Antartic",  "opt3" : "Artic"},
									{"question": "What is the Earth's Outer Layer called?",  "ans" : "Crust",  "opt1" : "Atmosphere",  "opt2" : "OZone",  "opt3" : "Milky Way"},
									{"question": "The Earth is surrounded by a blanket of air. What is it called?",  "ans" : "Atmosphere",  "opt1" : "Crust",  "opt2" : "OZone",  "opt3" : "Milky Way"},
									{"question": "Bamboo Forests grown in the South Western Mountains of China. What family does it belong to?",  "ans" : "Grass",  "opt1" : "Tree",  "opt2" : "Bush",  "opt3" : "Shrub"},
									{"question": "What is the only Grass that can actually grown in water?",  "ans" : "Rice",  "opt1" : "Wheat",  "opt2" : "Maize",  "opt3" : "Bermuda"},
									{"question": "How heavy, in kilograms, is a litre of water?",  "ans" : "One",  "opt1" : "Two",  "opt2" : "Three",  "opt3" : "Four"},
									{"question": "What is the term for a positive electrode?",  "ans" : "Anode",  "opt1" : "Electron",  "opt2" : "Proton",  "opt3" : "Neutron"},
									{"question": "Betz cells are found in which part of the body?",  "ans" : "Brain",  "opt1" : "Kidney",  "opt2" : "Liver",  "opt3" : "Abdomen"},
									{"question": "Which part of the eye gives it its colour?",  "ans" : "Iris",  "opt1" : "Retina",  "opt2" : "Cornea",  "opt3" : "Lashes"},
									{"question": "Which substance is most used for pencil lead?",  "ans" : "Graphite",  "opt1" : "Lead",  "opt2" : "Coal",  "opt3" : "Wood"},
									{"question": "At what speed in mph does a wind become a hurricane?",  "ans" : "73",  "opt1" : "50",  "opt2" : "100",  "opt3" : "200"},
									{"question": "Who first claimed that the world was not flat but a sphere?",  "ans" : "Pythagoras",  "opt1" : "Columbus",  "opt2" : "Newton",  "opt3" : "Copernicus"},
									{"question": "Who invented the  heliocentric model, that made the Sun at the center of the universe?",  "ans" : "Copernicus",  "opt1" : "Columbus",  "opt2" : "Newton",  "opt3" : "Edison"},
									{"question": "Who patented the first successful revolver in 1835?",  "ans" : "Samuel Colt",  "opt1" : " Jed Smith",  "opt2" : "Beethoven",  "opt3" : "Jonathon Thomson"},
									{"question": "This native New Yorker invented the elevator in 1850. Who was he?",  "ans" : "Henry Waterman",  "opt1" : "Christopher Gellar",  "opt2" : "Joseph Greene",  "opt3" : "Jonathon Thomson"},
									{"question": " Who published the first computer programs?",  "ans" : "Ada Byron",  "opt1" : "Jed Smith",  "opt2" : "Chris Johnson",  "opt3" : "L.D. Bartlett"},
									{"question": " The same guy who painted that enigmatic smile on Lisa created the parachute. What was his name?",  "ans" : "Leonardo da Vinci",  "opt1" : "Anton DaSilva",  "opt2" : "Beethoven",  "opt3" : "George Beluccia"},
									{"question": " The power lawn mover was invented by a man whose name evokes thoughts of robbery, blackmail, and lies. What was his name?",  "ans" : "Ransom Olds",  "opt1" : "Louis Robbe",  "opt2" : "Stealing Tophe",  "opt3" : "Gimme Money"},
									{"question": "Who invented Matches?",  "ans" : "John Walker",  "opt1" : "Jonathon Louis",  "opt2" : "Jeff Demsey",  "opt3" : "John Smith"},
									{"question": "Who invented the battery?",  "ans" : "Alessandro Volta",  "opt1" : "Thomas Edison",  "opt2" : "John Wilkinson",  "opt3" : "James Hargreaves"},
									{"question": "When was the first lawn mower invented?",  "ans" : "1830",  "opt1" : "1930",  "opt2" : "1950",  "opt3" : "1770"},
									{"question": "The shopping cart was invented by grocery store owner Sylvan Goldman of Oklahoma City. When were shopping carts first invented?",  "ans" : "1937",  "opt1" : "1947",  "opt2" : "1951",  "opt3" : "1932"},
									{"question": "What word came to be after a man in Ireland wrote on the walls of buildings one night in the 1700s?",  "ans" : "Quiz",  "opt1" : "Test",  "opt2" : "Spray Paint",  "opt3" : "Graffiti"},
									{"question": "Which decade was the bar code scanners invented?",  "ans" : "1970s",  "opt1" : "1950s",  "opt2" : "1960s",  "opt3" : "1940s"},
									{"question": "Where were wigs first invented?",  "ans" : "Egypt",  "opt1" : "Japan",  "opt2" : "France",  "opt3" : "China"},
									{"question": "When was the toothbrush invented?",  "ans" : "1770",  "opt1" : "1790",  "opt2" : "1742",  "opt3" : "1765"},
									{"question": "Who invented the phonograph?",  "ans" : "Thomas Edison",  "opt1" : "Alexander Graham Bell",  "opt2" : "Paul Ribaun",  "opt3" : "Jules Levy"},
									{"question": "Which decade was blue jeans invented?",  "ans" : "1850s",  "opt1" : "1770s",  "opt2" : "1900s",  "opt3" : "1660s"},
									{"question": "In 1809, fourteen years after Napoleon had offered a reward to anyone who could find a way of preserving food, a French confectioner by the name of Nicolas Appert did just that. What did he come up with?",  "ans" : "Cellophane wrapped",  "opt1" : "Canned",  "opt2" : "Dried",  "opt3" : "Frozen"},
									{"question": "In 1815 Sir Humphrey Davy invented something which was to save the lives of many miners. What was it?",  "ans" : "Lamp",  "opt1" : "Hat",  "opt2" : "Birdcage",  "opt3" : "Lift"},
									{"question": "A Hungarian obstetrician by the name of Ignaz Semmelweis lost his job as a result of his discovery in 1847 as he was implicated in many deaths. What had he discovered?",  "ans" : "Antiseptics",  "opt1" : "Blood transfusions",  "opt2" : "Forceps",  "opt3" : "Baby incubators"},
									{"question": "James Ritty's Pony House Restaurant was a successful establishment and in 1884 he came up with an idea to make it more profitable. What did he invent?",  "ans" : "Cash Register",  "opt1" : "Advertising Hoardings",  "opt2" : "Disposable plates",  "opt3" : "High Chair"},
									{"question": "In 1895 while testing the impact of passing electricity through bottles filled with gas, a German physicist, Wilhelm Roentgen discovered something. What did he discover?",  "ans" : "X Rays",  "opt1" : "Insulin",  "opt2" : "Laughing gas",  "opt3" : "Lasers"},
									{"question": "In 1868 an English railway engineer by the name of J.P Knight invented something which made its world debut outside London's Houses of Parliament. What did he devise?",  "ans" : "Traffic lights",  "opt1" : "Pedestrian crossing",  "opt2" : "Street lamp",  "opt3" : "Road sign"},
									{"question": "Cesare Lombroso, an Italian criminologist, made the first scientific attempt in 1895 to catch criminials using what method?",  "ans" : "Lie Detector",  "opt1" : "Identikit",  "opt2" : "Finger Prints",  "opt3" : "Undercover Surveillance"},
									{"question": "In 1890, what entertainment made its first appearance in San Francisco's Palais Royal Saloon?",  "ans" : "Jukebox",  "opt1" : "Pool Table",  "opt2" : "Pooker",  "opt3" : "Dart board"},
									{"question": "This invention came about as a result of a feud between two of the more prominent entrepreneurs of 1880s New York, George Westinghouse and Thomas Edison. Known as 'Old Sparky'. What was it?",  "ans" : "Electric Chair",  "opt1" : "Oven",  "opt2" : "Welder",  "opt3" : "Fax machine"},
									{"question": "When US President James Garfield was shot in 1881, which British born inventor used an early form of metal detector to try and locate the bullet in his body?",  "ans" : "Alexander Graham Bell",  "opt1" : " William Sturgeon",  "opt2" : "John Dunlop",  "opt3" : "Michael Faraday"},
									{"question": "Who invented the Telephone?",  "ans" : "Alexander Graham Bell",  "opt1" : " William Sturgeon",  "opt2" : "John Dunlop",  "opt3" : "Michael Faraday"},
									{"question": "ou've probably never heard the expression, 'the greatest inventor since Otto Rohwedder,' but you should have, since he was behind the invention of what convenient food item?",  "ans" : "Sliced Bread",  "opt1" : "Seedless Watermelon",  "opt2" : "Ketchup Bottle",  "opt3" : "Canned Food"},
									{"question": "Charles Strite didn't like the burnt toast served at the employee cafeteria, so he did something about it. What did he invent?",  "ans" : "Toaster",  "opt1" : "Kitchen timer",  "opt2" : "Kettle",  "opt3" : "Waffle Iron"},
									{"question": "Milk shakes wouldn't be possible without a device Stephen Poplawski invented in 1922. What is this invention?",  "ans" : "Electric Blender",  "opt1" : "Milk Pasteurizer",  "opt2" : "Whipped cream",  "opt3" : "Freezer"},
									{"question": "In 1858, Ezra Warner patented a device with a large curved blade and a bent shaft. What was it used for?",  "ans" : "Opening cans",  "opt1" : "Cutting grapefruit",  "opt2" : "Slicing bread",  "opt3" : "Peeling bananas"},
									{"question": "Some inventions happen by accident, which is what happened to Percy Spencer when he found a candy bar melted in his pocket. What invention did this lead to?",  "ans" : "Microwave oven",  "opt1" : "Insulated lunch box",  "opt2" : "Candy coated chocolates",  "opt3" : "Easy bake oven"},
									{"question": "Watching a cook mix dough was the inspiration behind Herbert Johnson inventing what device in 1908?",  "ans" : "Mixer",  "opt1" : "Rolling pin",  "opt2" : "Waffle iron",  "opt3" : "Electric blender"},
									{"question": "Professor Doctor Carl van Linde was one cool character. He was the first to patent and produce a practical what?",  "ans" : "Refrigerator",  "opt1" : "Mechanical dishwasher",  "opt2" : "Microwave oven",  "opt3" : "Electric blender"},
									{"question": "Josephine Cochran was a frustrated socialite. She loved hosting dinner parties, but not cleaning up after them - so what did she invent?",  "ans" : "Dishwasher",  "opt1" : "Paper plates",  "opt2" : "Rubber gloves",  "opt3" : "Vacuum cleaner"},
									{"question": "A DuPont chemist named Earl Tupper turned inflexible polyethylene slag leftovers into something that could be used to store kitchen leftovers. He received a 1945 patent for what invention?",  "ans" : "Tupperware",  "opt1" : "Zip-lock bags",  "opt2" : "Aluminum foil",  "opt3" : "Doggie bag"},
									{"question": "As per Albert Einstein's famous equation regarding relativity, what is 'E equals m times c squared' equal to?",  "ans" : "Energy",  "opt1" : "Light",  "opt2" : "Mass",  "opt3" : "Time"},
									{"question": "Who is often called the 'Father of Modern Science'  because he wrote down his experiments?",  "ans" : "Roger Bacon",  "opt1" : "Newton",  "opt2" : "Einstein",  "opt3" : "Alexander Graham Bell"},
									{"question": "Who discovered that a Gun Powder would explode in confined space if its burnt?",  "ans" : "Roger Bacon",  "opt1" : "Newton",  "opt2" : "Einstein",  "opt3" : "Alexander Graham Bell "},
									{"question": "The Swedish scientist Alfred Nobel is most famous today for creating the Nobel Prize. What invention made him rich?",  "ans" : "Dynamite",  "opt1" : "Stainless Steel",  "opt2" : "Spam",  "opt3" : "Dry Ice"},
									{"question": "In 1828, Friedrich Woehler performed the first chemical synthesis of a naturally occurring biologic (organic) molecule. What did he synthesize?",  "ans" : "Urea",  "opt1" : "Cheez-Wiz",  "opt2" : "Alanine",  "opt3" : "Glucose"},
									{"question": "The 19th century Russian chemist Dmitri Mendeleyev arranged cards that described all known chemical elements into what?",  "ans" : "Periodic Table",  "opt1" : "Acid Base Pair",  "opt2" : "Four Quantum states",  "opt3" : "The words 'I hate borscht'"},
									{"question": "The German scientist Max Planck by studying light of different frequencies, he proposed the existence of quanta that carried discrete but small amounts of what?",  "ans" : "Energy",  "opt1" : "Color",  "opt2" : "Randomness",  "opt3" : "Pressure"},
									{"question": "In 300 B.C.E., Theophrastus described asbestos as 'a substance resembling rotting wood which, when doused with oil, would burn without being harmed.' Where does asbestos come from?",  "ans" : "Mines",  "opt1" : "Plant",  "opt2" : "Sea",  "opt3" : "Glass"},
									{"question": "In 1775, when Benjamin Franklin traveled from England to America he measured the temperature of the water at many points and  discovered a region of warm water due to what?",  "ans" : "Gulf Stream",  "opt1" : "Shallow Water",  "opt2" : "Thermal vents",  "opt3" : "O-Zone Layer"},
									{"question": "In 1858, Charles Darwin proposed what theory to explain the diversity of living things on earth?",  "ans" : "Natural Selection",  "opt1" : "Acquired characteristics",  "opt2" : "DNA mutagenesis",  "opt3" : "Alien insemination"},
									{"question": "In 1803, John Dalton proposed that all substances are composed of small, dense, indestructible particles known as what?",  "ans" : "Atoms",  "opt1" : "Daltons",  "opt2" : "Molecules",  "opt3" : "Electrons"},
									{"question": "In 1932, James Chadwick discovered what subatomic particle that contains mass but no charge?",  "ans" : "Neutron",  "opt1" : "Alpha",  "opt2" : "Proton",  "opt3" : "Electron"},
									{"question": "The 'Two body problem' was first solved by?",  "ans" : "Newton",  "opt1" : "Liebnitz",  "opt2" : "Adam",  "opt3" : "Einstein"},
									{"question": " Galileo was excommunicated from the Catholic Church for saying what was the center of the Universe?",  "ans" : "Sun",  "opt1" : "Earth",  "opt2" : "Moon",  "opt3" : "Mars"},
									{"question": "Wright brothers invented the flying Machine. One was called Wilbur what was the other brothers name?",  "ans" : "Orville",  "opt1" : "John",  "opt2" : "Oliver",  "opt3" : "Brian"},
									{"question": "Which decade was Newton born?",  "ans" : "1640s",  "opt1" : "1750s",  "opt2" : "1800s",  "opt3" : "1450s"},
									{"question": "Who invented the motion picture camera?",  "ans" : "Edison",  "opt1" : "Wright Brothers",  "opt2" : "Einstein",  "opt3" : "Newton"},
									{"question": "Coca Cola originally was sold as a medicine.It was invented in the late 19th century by whom?",  "ans" : "John Pemberton",  "opt1" : "Asa Griggs",  "opt2" : "Edison",  "opt3" : "Einstein"}        
        ],
        "Sports": [
        
									{"question": "Which French footballer scored twice in the 1998 World Cup final?",  "ans" : "Zinedine Zidane",  "opt1" : "Marcel Desailly",  "opt2" : "Emmanuel Petit",  "opt3" : "Patrick Vieira"},
									{"question": " Before thousands of adoring Scots at St. Andrews, who took the 1978 British Open to become the first golfer with at least three titles in each of the four pro majors?",  "ans" : "Jack Nicklaus",  "opt1" : "Arnold Palmer",  "opt2" : "Tom Watson",  "opt3" : "Gary Player"},
									{"question": "How many Gold Medals did American athlete Jesse Owens win in 1936 Berlin Olympics?",  "ans" : "4",  "opt1" : "3",  "opt2" : "2",  "opt3" : "1"},
									{"question": "The first Super Bowl occurred on January 15, 1967, pitting the Green Bay Packers against the Kansas City Chiefs. Which NFL team was the first to lose three Super Bowls?",  "ans" : "Minnesota Vikings",  "opt1" : "Arizona Cardinals",  "opt2" : "Green Bay Packers",  "opt3" : "Philadelphia Eagles"},
									{"question": "Hall of Fame and Baltimore Colt quarterback Johnny Unitas spent 17 of his 18 seasons with the horseshoe on his helmet. Which team did he retire with in 1973?",  "ans" : "San Diego Chargers",  "opt1" : "St. Louis Rams",  "opt2" : "Pittsburgh Steelers",  "opt3" : "Chicago Bears"},
									{"question": "Which of these running back greats rushed for more yardage in their career?",  "ans" : "Franco Harris",  "opt1" : "Jim Taylor",  "opt2" : "Earl Campbell",  "opt3" : "Priest Holmes"},
									{"question": "In what country was Bjorn Borg born?",  "ans" : "Sweden",  "opt1" : "Denmark",  "opt2" : "Norway",  "opt3" : "Finland"},
									{"question": "How would Borg's adult tennis playing style be best described?",  "ans" : "Baseliner",  "opt1" : "Hacker",  "opt2" : "Serve and Volley",  "opt3" : "Counter-puncher"},
									{"question": "Which Grand Slam did Bjorn Borg win the most times?",  "ans" : "French Open",  "opt1" : "U.S. Open",  "opt2" : "Wimbledon",  "opt3" : "Australian Open"},
									{"question": "Which of the following players did Bjorn Borg have a great rivalry with?",  "ans" : "Mats Wilander",  "opt1" : "Roger Federer",  "opt2" : "Stan Smith",  "opt3" : "John McEnroe"},
									{"question": "What material were Borg's rackets made of throughout his professional career?",  "ans" : "Wood",  "opt1" : "Carbon fibre",  "opt2" : "Titanium alloys",  "opt3" : " Steel"},
									{"question": "The first modern day Olympic games were held in Athens in 1896. The most famous of the Greek winners was Spiridon Louis. Which event did he win?",  "ans" : "Marathon",  "opt1" : "100 meters",  "opt2" : "Discus throw",  "opt3" : "High jump"},
									{"question": "Nadia Comaneci was only 14 years old when she gained 3 gold medals at the uneven bars, the balance beam, and the all around gymnastics title. In which year did she do this in the Montreal Olympics?",  "ans" : "1976",  "opt1" : "1972",  "opt2" : "1980",  "opt3" : "1984"},
									{"question": "In Beijing in 2008, Michael Phelps gained 8 gold medals, setting a record for most won gold medals in a single Olympic Game. The old record was also held by a swimmer. Who was it?",  "ans" : "Mark Spitz",  "opt1" : "John Weismuller",  "opt2" : "Michael Phelps",  "opt3" : "Matt Biondi"},
									{"question": "The 1998 World Cup marked only the second time that a European nation defeated a South American nation in a World Cup final. When was the first?",  "ans" : "1990",  "opt1" : "1938",  "opt2" : "1954",  "opt3" : "1982"},
									{"question": "Excluding the 3rd place match, how many goals did Turkish striker Hakan Sukur score in the 2002 World Cup?",  "ans" : "0",  "opt1" : "1",  "opt2" : "2",  "opt3" : "3"},
									{"question": "The 1986 World Cup quarterfinal between Brazil and France was decided on a penalty shootout after the match ended 1-1. Who scored the goals in regulation time?",  "ans" : "Platini Careca",  "opt1" : "Tigana Socrates",  "opt2" : "Fernandez Zico",  "opt3" : "Giresse Branco"},
									{"question": "Arrigo Sacchi coached the AC Milan team to the 1989 and 1990 European Cups. At which World Cup did he coach Italy?",  "ans" : "1994",  "opt1" : "1986",  "opt2" : "1990",  "opt3" : "1998"},
									{"question": "Italy won the 1938 World Cup, but which country was the runners up?",  "ans" : "Hungary",  "opt1" : "Brazil",  "opt2" : "France",  "opt3" : "Sweden"},
									{"question": "Which country won the 1962 World Cup?",  "ans" : "Brazil",  "opt1" : "Yugoslavia",  "opt2" : "Czechoslovakia",  "opt3" : "Chile"},
									{"question": "In 1990, West Germany won the World Cup. Who was the German manager?",  "ans" : "Franz Beckenbauer",  "opt1" : "Sepp Herberger",  "opt2" : "Helmut Schoen",  "opt3" : "Berti Vogts"},
									{"question": "Which team won the World Cup in 1954?",  "ans" : "West Germany",  "opt1" : "U.S.A",  "opt2" : "Hungary",  "opt3" : "Scotland"},
									{"question": "In the 1994 final between Brazil and Italy, the Cup was won by which method?",  "ans" : "Penalties",  "opt1" : "Golden goal",  "opt2" : "Extra-Time",  "opt3" : "Team that had more corners"},
									{"question": "Who did Argentina beat in the final of the World Cup in 1978?",  "ans" : "Netherlands",  "opt1" : "Scotland",  "opt2" : "Germany",  "opt3" : "Italy"},
									{"question": "What was the attendance at the Romania v Peru match in the 1930 World Cup in Uruguay?",  "ans" : "300",  "opt1" : "1500",  "opt2" : "700",  "opt3" : "1000"},
									{"question": "Who scored against France in 27 seconds in the 1982 World Cup?",  "ans" : "Bryan Robson",  "opt1" : "Glenn Hoddle",  "opt2" : "Kevin Keegan",  "opt3" : "Trevor Brooking"},
									{"question": "In what year were substitutes used for the first time in the World Cup?",  "ans" : "1970",  "opt1" : "1966",  "opt2" : "1958",  "opt3" : "1982"},
									{"question": "The late Sir Bobby Robson reminisced about that ill fated moment in the 1986 FIFA World Cup quarterfinal against Argentina. Who was the late Sir Bobby Robson referring to?",  "ans" : "Diego Maradona",  "opt1" : "Carlos Bilardo",  "opt2" : "Jorge Valdano",  "opt3" : "Ali Bin Nasser"},
									{"question": "In stroke play, what is the penalty when a player hits a putt from the green and the ball strikes another player's ball on the putting surface?",  "ans" : "Two",  "opt1" : "None",  "opt2" : "Disqualification",  "opt3" : "One"},
									{"question": "What Golf event was originally planned to coincide with sportswriters travelling between Florida and New York after baseball's spring training?",  "ans" : "Masters",  "opt1" : "The Doral Open",  "opt2" : "Tournament Players Championship",  "opt3" : "North and South Open"},
									{"question": "Before turning 50 and becoming elgible for the Senior Tour, for what network did Lee Trevino serve as a golf commentator?",  "ans" : "NBC",  "opt1" : "ESPN",  "opt2" : "ABC",  "opt3" : "CBS"},
									{"question": "What president had a tree, that he wanted removed from the 17th hole at Augusta National, named after him instead?",  "ans" : "Eisenhower",  "opt1" : "Ford",  "opt2" : "Kennedy",  "opt3" : "Nixon"},
									{"question": "What legend caddied for son Gary in a '93 pro tourney and after fighting blisters and fatigue said, 'The first time I've carried a bag since college. I like playing better'?",  "ans" : "Jack Nicklaus",  "opt1" : "Greg Norman",  "opt2" : "Ray Floyd",  "opt3" : "Gary Player"},
									{"question": "What is the maximum number of clubs a player may carry?",  "ans" : "14",  "opt1" : "12",  "opt2" : "10",  "opt3" : "15"},
									{"question": "What legend has the distinction of being the only player to lose three US Open playoffs?",  "ans" : "Arnold Palmer",  "opt1" : "Tom Watson",  "opt2" : "Sam Snead",  "opt3" : "Robert Ashley"},
									{"question": "In the 2006 season, which team shared the honor by tacking up the most shutouts in the season?",  "ans" : "Jacksonville Jaguars",  "opt1" : "Tampa Bay Buccaneers",  "opt2" : "Detroit Lions",  "opt3" : "Oakland Raiders"},
									{"question": "Point after touchdowns (PATs) seem to be a frivolous item in the NFL. Which kicker set a NFL record by attempting 10 PATs in one game in the 1960s?",  "ans" : "Charlie Gogolak",  "opt1" : "Otis Taylor",  "opt2" : "Warren Wells",  "opt3" : "Don Maynard"},
									{"question": "Which team won the first AFL championship?",  "ans" : "Houston Oilers",  "opt1" : "Cleveland Browns",  "opt2" : "Green Bay Packers",  "opt3" : "Dallas Cowboys"},
									{"question": "Which kicker set a record for leading the league in kicking the most field goals in a season, five times?",  "ans" : "Lou Groza",  "opt1" : "Marrio Grier",  "opt2" : "Ottis Anderson",  "opt3" : "Corey Dillon"},
									{"question": "Who was the first running back to carry the ball 4000 times in a career?",  "ans" : "Emmitt Smith",  "opt1" : "Tony Dorsett",  "opt2" : "Franco Harris",  "opt3" : "John Riggins"},
									{"question": "Which team set a record for playing 24 consecutive games without losing one?",  "ans" : "Canton Bulldogs",  "opt1" : "Green Bay Packers",  "opt2" : "Buffalo Braves",  "opt3" : "Miami Dolphins"},
									{"question": "When the first African-American quarterback of NFL joined the Rams in 1973, the team ran off a streak of winning in double-figures for the next six seasons. Who was this quarterback?",  "ans" : "James Harris",  "opt1" : "Bill Wade",  "opt2" : "John Hadl",  "opt3" : "Buddy Humphrey"},
									{"question": "Who was the head coach of the Cleveland Browns during the 1950s?",  "ans" : "George Allen",  "opt1" : "Paul Brown",  "opt2" : "Raymond Berry",  "opt3" : "Soupy Sales"},
									{"question": "Which team was the first to win a Super Bowl by more than 40 points?",  "ans" : "San Francisco 49ers",  "opt1" : "Buffalo Bills",  "opt2" : "Pittsburgh Steelers",  "opt3" : "Atlanta Falcons"},
									{"question": "During Week 12 of the 2008 season, who set a new record with his 108-yard TD interception?",  "ans" : "Ed Reed",  "opt1" : "Flozell Adams",  "opt2" : "Ken Amato",  "opt3" : "Jim Otto"},
									{"question": "The San Diego Chargers went to their first Super Bowl in 1995 with Super XXIX, but lost to the San Francisco 49ers. Who was the head coach of the Chargers?",  "ans" : "Bobby Ross",  "opt1" : "Joe Robbie",  "opt2" : "George Halas",  "opt3" : "Joe Torre"},
									{"question": "Who was the first career Cincinnati Bengal to be inducted into pro football's Hall of Fame?",  "ans" : "Anthony Munoz",  "opt1" : "James Brooks",  "opt2" : "Boomer Esiason",  "opt3" : "Essex Johnson"},
									{"question": "If a Pittsburgh Steeler kicked a field goal with the ball hiked from the 50-yard line and made it, how long was the actual field goal?",  "ans" : "67",  "opt1" : "50",  "opt2" : "55",  "opt3" : "60"},
									{"question": "Of the three Grand Tours, which is the oldest?",  "ans" : "Tour de France",  "opt1" : "Giro d'Italia",  "opt2" : "Vuelta a Espana",  "opt3" : "They all are the same age"},
									{"question": "Who was the first cyclist to win the Vuelta a Espana three times in a row?",  "ans" : "Tony Rominger",  "opt1" : "Roberto Heras",  "opt2" : "Denis Menchov",  "opt3" : "Alex Zulle"},
									{"question": "In Tour De France the rider with the lowest aggregate time at the end of each day wears what colour jersey.",  "ans" : "Yellow",  "opt1" : "Blue",  "opt2" : "Green",  "opt3" : "Polka-dot"},
									{"question": "Who was the first rider to win a Grand Tour by a margin of under 10 seconds?",  "ans" : "Eric Caritoux",  "opt1" : "Fiorenzo Magni",  "opt2" : "Greg LeMond",  "opt3" : "Laurent Jalabert"},
									{"question": "Which of the following riders was the first to win a total of 11 Grand Tours?",  "ans" : "Eddy Merckx",  "opt1" : "Jacques Anquetil",  "opt2" : "Bernard Hinault",  "opt3" : "Lance Armstrong"},
									{"question": "Riders of what nationality were the first to win all three Grand Tours?",  "ans" : "Italian",  "opt1" : "Spanish",  "opt2" : "French",  "opt3" : "Luxembourgian"},
									{"question": "Who was the first cyclist to win all three Grand Tours?",  "ans" : "Jacques Anquetil",  "opt1" : "Alberto Contador",  "opt2" : "Bernard Hinault",  "opt3" : "Eddy Merckx"},
									{"question": "Who was the first to win a stage in all three Grand Tours in the same year?",  "ans" : "Miguel Poblet",  "opt1" : "Erik Zabel",  "opt2" : "Mark Cavendish",  "opt3" : "Alessandro Petacchi"},
									{"question": "Who was the first NBA player to win five season MVP awards?",  "ans" : "Bill Russell",  "opt1" : "Vlade Divac",  "opt2" : "Charles Barkley",  "opt3" : "LeBron James"},
									{"question": "The Boston Celtics won the NBA Championship for the 2007-08 season. Who did they defeat?",  "ans" : "Lakers",  "opt1" : "Grizzlies",  "opt2" : "Wizards",  "opt3" : "Clippers"},
									{"question": "Who was the first-ever number one overall draft pick in NBA history in 1950?",  "ans" : "Chuck Share",  "opt1" : "Nate Thurmond",  "opt2" : "Elgin Baylor",  "opt3" : "Rajon Rondo"},
									{"question": "What was Kareem Abdul-Jabbar's born first name?",  "ans" : "Ferdinand",  "opt1" : "Louis",  "opt2" : "Robert",  "opt3" : "William"},
									{"question": "The first Coach of the Year Award was presented for the 1962-63 season. Which coach won the award?",  "ans" : "Harry Gallatin",  "opt1" : "Gene Shue",  "opt2" : "Lenny Wilkens",  "opt3" : "Pat Riley"},
									{"question": "Which team won the first-ever NBA Championship in 1950?",  "ans" : "Lakers",  "opt1" : "Royals",  "opt2" : "Supersonics",  "opt3" : "Heat"},
									{"question": "The Sixth Man Award was first presented for the 1982-83 season. Which Philadelphia 76er won the inaugural award?",  "ans" : "Billy Cunningham",  "opt1" : "Jerry Lucas",  "opt2" : "Bobby Jones",  "opt3" : "Manute Bol"},
									{"question": "In in 1990 he scored more points than any other player in NBA history. Name the Player?",  "ans" : "Kareem Abdul Jabbar",  "opt1" : "Oscar Robertson",  "opt2" : "Tim Duncan",  "opt3" : "Walt Bellamy"},
									{"question": "At 7 foot 1 inch he played for the Harlem Globetrotters prior to playing in the NBA. During his career he held many records and he died in 1999. Name the player? ",  "ans" : "Wilt Chamberlain",  "opt1" : "Bailey Howell",  "opt2" : "Hal Greer",  "opt3" : "Rick Barry"},
									{"question": "Before entering into the Major Leagues, this player was with the Indianapolis Clowns of the Negro Leagues. Who was is this Hall of Famer?",  "ans" : "Hank Aaron",  "opt1" : "Willie Mays",  "opt2" : "Satchel Paige",  "opt3" : "Ernie Banks"},
									{"question": "This pitcher was the first to win the Cy Young award in both the American and National Leagues. Over 22 seasons he played for eight teams. Who was this 1991 Hall of Fame inductee?",  "ans" : "Gaylord Perry",  "opt1" : "Roger Clemens",  "opt2" : "Tom Seaver",  "opt3" : "Whitey Ford"},
									{"question": "From 1915-1920, which Hall of Fame pitcher won three Triple Crowns?",  "ans" : "Pete Alexander",  "opt1" : "Dazzy Vance",  "opt2" : "Don Newcombe",  "opt3" : "Cy Young"},
									{"question": "He  was one of the greatest shortstops in baseball, and in 1948 won the American League MVP. He also helped the Indians to a World Series title in the season. Who was this eight-time all-star?",  "ans" : "Lou Boudreau",  "opt1" : "Duke Snider",  "opt2" : "Paul Waner",  "opt3" : "Joe Medwick"},
									{"question": "I played baseball for 16 seasons, but it was my managing that put me in the Hall of Fame. I managed the New York Giants for 31 seasons, winning 10 NL pennants. Who am I?",  "ans" : "John McGraw",  "opt1" : "Bill Rigney",  "opt2" : "Billy Martin",  "opt3" : "Miller Huggins"},
									{"question": "He and fellow Hall of Famer Josh Gibson, led their Homestead Grays to dominate the Negro Leagues in the late 1930s. Who was this 1972 Hall of Fame inductee?",  "ans" : "Buck Leonard",  "opt1" : "Joe Sewell",  "opt2" : "Firpo Marberry",  "opt3" : "Harry Heilmann"},
									{"question": "This player was known as 'Mr. Second Base'. He won the 1959 AL MVP with the White Sox. His only World Series was in 1959 to watch his White Sox lose to the Dodgers. Who was he?",  "ans" : "Nellie Fox",  "opt1" : "Joe Morgan",  "opt2" : "Bill Mazeroski",  "opt3" : "Rusty Staub"},
									{"question": "Like Reggie Jackson in 1993, I was inducted all by myself in 1988. I was a 21-season career Pittsburgh Pirate outfielder and first baseman. My nickname was 'Pops'. Who am I?",  "ans" : "Willie Stargell",  "opt1" : "Roberto Clemente",  "opt2" : "Bill Mazeroski",  "opt3" : "Jack Popsum"},
									{"question": "'Melon-head' is the nickname given to which  tennis player?",  "ans" : "Thomas Enqvist",  "opt1" : " Mark Philippoussis",  "opt2" : "Todd Martin",  "opt3" : "Roger Federer"},
									{"question": "Which US tennis player made a guest apperance in an episode of 'Sabrina, the Teenage Witch'?",  "ans" : "Andy Roddick",  "opt1" : "Pete Sampras",  "opt2" : "Andre Agassi",  "opt3" : "Jan-michael Gambill"},
									{"question": "Which tennis player has a daughter named Lola?",  "ans" : "Sebastien Grosjean",  "opt1" : "Richard Krajicek",  "opt2" : "Yevgeny Kafelnikov",  "opt3" : "Tim Henman"},
									{"question": "Which tennis player has a tattoo of a shark and roses over a cross on his back?",  "ans" : "Goran Ivanisevic",  "opt1" : "Mark Philippoussis",  "opt2" : "Gustavo Kuerten",  "opt3" : "Marcelo Rios"},
									{"question": "Who coaches Jan-michael Gambill?",  "ans" : "Father",  "opt1" : "Brother",  "opt2" : "Uncle",  "opt3" : " Nobody"},
									{"question": "Which cricket batsman was the first-ever to score 50 Test centuries, and reached this milestone in 2010?",  "ans" : "Sachin Tendulkar",  "opt1" : "Tim Duncan",  "opt2" : "Donald Bradman",  "opt3" : "Rafael Nadal"},
									{"question": "The number 2 is dedicated to which country, who in 1999 won their second Rugby Union World Cup?",  "ans" : "Australia",  "opt1" : "Greece",  "opt2" : "Italy",  "opt3" : "Canada"},
									{"question": "The number 3 was immortalized in the baseball world by this player who wore the number 3 on his back, and who hit 714 career home runs. Who is this Hall of Fame great?",  "ans" : "Babe Ruth",  "opt1" : "Sadaharu Oh",  "opt2" : "Gale Sayers",  "opt3" : "George Mikan"},
									{"question": "The number 4 is dedicated to this tremendous Indianpolis 500 race car driver, who won the race four times in his career. Who is this driver?",  "ans" : "Al Unser",  "opt1" : "Mark Spitz",  "opt2" : "Jeff Gordon",  "opt3" : "Ronnie O'Sullivan"},
									{"question": "The number 5 is in honor of this Major League Baseball team, who won five consecutive World Series crowns in the 1940s and 1950s. Which team was this?",  "ans" : "New York Yankees",  "opt1" : "Boston Red Sox",  "opt2" : "Pittsburgh Steelers",  "opt3" : "Wolverhampton Wanderers"},
									{"question": "The number 7 is in honor of the first National Football League team to make seven Super Bowl appearances. Which team was this?",  "ans" : "Pittsburgh Steelers",  "opt1" : "Oakland Athletics",  "opt2" : "Buffalo Bills",  "opt3" : "New York Knicks"},
									{"question": "The number 8 is dedicated to this American NBA Basketball team which won an amazing eight consecutive NBA Championship titles. Which team was this?",  "ans" : "Boston Celtics",  "opt1" : "Sydney Tigers",  "opt2" : "Atlanta Braves",  "opt3" : "Macarthur Rams"},
									{"question": "In 1999, the number 9 flowed well, and saw this English soccer team win its ninth FA Cup. Which powerhouse was this?",  "ans" : "Manchester United",  "opt1" : "Glasgow",  "opt2" : "London",  "opt3" : "Arsenal"},
									{"question": "The number 10 is in honor of this left-handed professional bowler, who won 10 professional major titles in his career. Who was this crew-cut wearing bowler who died in 2001?",  "ans" : "Earl Anthony",  "opt1" : "Mark Roth",  "opt2" : "Bart Starr",  "opt3" : "Andrew Flintoff"},
									{"question": "The number 11 is dedicated to this American National Basketball Association coach who was the first to win 11 NBA Championships. Who is this coach?",  "ans" : "Phil Jackson",  "opt1" : "Pete Weber",  "opt2" : "Arnold Palmer",  "opt3" : "Isiah Thomas"},
									{"question": "The number 12 refers to which professional tennis great who won her 12th Grand Slam tennis title in 2010?",  "ans" : "Serena Williams",  "opt1" : "Margaret Court",  "opt2" : "Steffi Graf",  "opt3" : "Martina Navratilova"},
									{"question": "13 is superstitious to some, but not this National Football League quarterback who wore the number 13 throughout his career with the Miami Dolphins.Who is this Hall of Fame quarterback?",  "ans" : "Dan Marino",  "opt1" : "Don Bradman",  "opt2" : "Richard Petty",  "opt3" : "Lou Gehrig"},
									{"question": "The number 14 is dedicated to this professional tennis player who tied a record with his 14th major singles title at the French Open. Which tennis player was this in 2009?",  "ans" : "Roger Federer",  "opt1" : "John McEnroe",  "opt2" : "Pete Sampras",  "opt3" : "Sam Snead"},
									{"question": "The number 15 is in honor of the 15th championship that this NHRA racing driver won in 2010. Who is this drag racing great?",  "ans" : "John Force",  "opt1" : "Alex Rodriguez",  "opt2" : "Alan Kulwicki",  "opt3" : "Gary Player"},
									{"question": "The number 17 is dedicated to the first American National Basketball Association team to win 17 NBA Championships. Which basketball team was this in 2008?",  "ans" : "Boston Celtics",  "opt1" : "Philadelphia Eagles",  "opt2" : "San Antonio Spurs",  "opt3" : "Florida Marlins"},
									{"question": "This number 18 was seen on the door of this 2010 NASCAR driver. After a promising 2009 season, he did not fare well in 2010. Who was this Joe Gibbs racing team driver?",  "ans" : "Kyle Busch",  "opt1" : "Don Prudhomme",  "opt2" : "Willis Reed",  "opt3" : "Ricky Ponting"},
									{"question": "The number 19 is dedicated to this National Hockey League 2010 Chicago Blackhawk captain. He was the third overall pick in the 2006 NHL draft. Who is this?",  "ans" : "Jonathan Toews",  "opt1" : "Shane Warne",  "opt2" : "Bobby Hull",  "opt3" : "Donovan McNabb"},
									{"question": "The number 20 is in honor of T20 cricket. Who was the first cricketer to score a century in a T20 international match?",  "ans" : "Chris Gayle",  "opt1" : "Wilt Chamberlain",  "opt2" : "Sunil Gavaskar",  "opt3" : "Roy Halladay"},
									{"question": "The number 21 is dedicated to this Major League Baseball player who was killed in a plane crash during a humanitarian mission, to fly relief supplies to Nicaragua in 1972. Who was this?",  "ans" : "Roberto Clemente",  "opt1" : "Jack Nicklaus",  "opt2" : "Mickey Mantle",  "opt3" : "Walter Payton"},
									{"question": "The number 22 is a historical number, as in 1922. This was the first season of America's National Football League. Which team won the first-ever NFL Championship?",  "ans" : "Canton Bulldogs",  "opt1" : "Chicago White Sox",  "opt2" : "Green Bay Packers",  "opt3" : "Cincinnati Reds"},
									{"question": "The number 23 was created and is known worldwide being worn by a Hall of Fame American NBA Basketball player. Who was this that played for the Chicago Bulls?",  "ans" : "Michael Jordan",  "opt1" : "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",  "opt2" : "Juan Montoya",  "opt3" : "Derek Jeter"},
									{"question": "The number 24 is dedicated to this NASCAR racing driver who had the number 24 on the side of his car. Being well known for his association with DuPont as a sponsor, who is this?",  "ans" : "Jeff Gordon",  "opt1" : "John Havlicek",  "opt2" : "Vivian Richards",  "opt3" : "Albert Pujols"},
									{"question": "The number 25 is in honor of a baseball player who went on to break Hank Aaron's career home run record. Who was this San Francisco Giant?",  "ans" : "Barry Bonds",  "opt1" : "Dennis Rodman",  "opt2" : "Reggie Jackson",  "opt3" : "Emmitt Smith"}        

        ]
		}
}